1957年10月 蘇聯將
In October 1957, the Soviet Union launched
世界上第一顆人造衛星 斯普特尼克1號送入軌道
the world's first artificial satellite, Sputnik 1, into orbit.
這一成就加劇了美蘇兩國之間的太空競賽
Their achievement fueled a space race between the United States and the Soviets.
之後發生了什麼 人們說法不一
There has been some debate about what followed
但我親身經歷過 所以接下來講的都是真事 基本上是吧
but I was there, and this is the real story. Mostly.
直到兩天前
Until two days ago,
地球上的人才頭一次聽到這個聲音
that sound had never been heard on this earth.
(蘇聯人將衛星送進太空)
(《生活》 太空競賽)
(美國衛星一敗塗地)
美國嘗試發射自己的衛星 結果慘不忍睹
(美國火箭計劃啟動失敗)
蘇聯成功地將一個人送入太空
The Soviet Union has sent a man into space
(第一個進入太空的人)
並把他活著帶回地球
and brought him back alive.
蘇聯人在全世界範圍內
The Soviets made the most of the flight
大肆宣傳這次航天行動 其國內自然也是舉國歡慶
in their worldwide propaganda. Naturally, there was jubilation in Russia.
在認識到蘇聯人取得領先後
Recognizing the head start obtained by the Soviets,
我認為我國應致力於實現一個目標
I believe that this nation should commit itself to achieving the goal,
即在這個十年內
before this decade is out,
把一個人送上月球並讓他安全返回地球
of landing a man on the moon and returning him safely to the earth.
(美國宇航員環繞地球飛行)
我們選擇在這個十年登月
We choose to go to the moon in this decade
並完成其他壯舉 不是因為這個目標輕而易舉
and do the other things, not because they are easy,
而是因為它困難重重
but because they are hard.
因為這個挑戰是我們願意接受
Because that challenge is one that we are willing to accept,
不願推遲 並準備大獲全勝的
one we are unwilling to postpone, and one we intend to win.
指揮飛行員 一 二 三 四 五
Command Pilot. One, two, three, four, five.
五 四 三 二 一
Five, four, three, two, one.
著火了
Flame!
駕駛艙裏失火了
We've got a fire in the cockpit.
快出去 我們要燒死了
Let's get out! We're burning up!
宇航員維吉爾·格裏森 愛德華·懷特 和羅傑·查菲不幸遇難
Astronauts Virgil Grissom, Edward White and Roger Chaffee have been killed.
媒體官員稱 因為此次悲劇事件
Press officials say because of the tragedy,
阿波羅1號飛行任務將被無限期推遲
the Apollo 1 flight has now been postponed indefinitely.
我... 登月之旅很有吸引力
I... It's, uh... It's a groovy trip,
但在美國 還有很多更重要的事情要先做
but there are a lot more important things to do first in the United States.
也許把這些事情都搞定了 我們才能登月
Maybe when all that's taken care of we can afford to go to the moon.
我們發現自己物質豐富 士氣低下
We find ourselves rich in goods but ragged in spirit.
雄心勃勃地想要登月
Reaching with magnificent precision for the moon
卻在地球上陷入一片混亂
but falling into raucous discord on earth.
我們想要和平 卻被捲入戰爭
We are caught at war wanting peace.
我們想要團結 卻四分五裂
We're torn by division wanting unity.
這個巨大的土星號火箭
This giant Saturn rocket
以及這裏的其他設備 最初都是這場競賽的一部分
and the rest of the equipment here began as part of a race
(國家航空航天局預算削減)
為的是戰勝蘇聯人 它們肩負著
to beat the Russians with the national goal
我國在這個十年內把人類送上月球的目標
of putting a man on the moon in this decade.
但登月之旅的花費將超出所有人的預期
But their trip will cost more than anyone thought it would.
而在1960年代成功登月的幾率愈加渺茫
And their chances of landing on the moon in the 1960s are increasingly slim.
(國家航空航天局)
斯圖 你當主管第一周 聽著情況不妙啊
First week as manager, Stu. Doesn't sound like it's going great.
要麼是計量表不准 要麼是某個儲存罐漏了
So either our meters are off or there's a breach in one of the tanks.
但這種情況沒有規程 我們也找不到洩漏源頭
But there's no protocol for this. And we can't source the leak
因為是液態... 液態氫
because it's liquid hyd... Liquid hydrogen.
它是無色無味的 所有人都出去 快
It's colorless and odorless. Everybody out! Let's go!
裏德 凱爾 放下鉛筆
Reed, Kyle, pencils down.
可能已經在燃燒了 我們卻不知情 找門出去
It could be burning, and we wouldn't know it. Find a door.
快 跑起來 別慢吞吞的
Come on! Run, run! No walking.
他在幹什麼? 打掃嗎?
What's he doing? Is he cleaning?
不... 這是... 一種檢查洩漏的老辦法
No, no. It's an... It's an old-school leak detection process.
他用的是把掃帚
It's a broom.
斯圖 你很聰明的 再想想 干麥稈加上液態氫等於...
Stu, you're better than this. Come on. Straw plus liquid hydrogen equals...
好 沒事了 別擔心了 來吧
All right, we're good! Don't worry about it. Come on.
我們還有工作呢 快點
We got work to do. Let's go.
新的規程是用掃帚檢查洩漏
Uh, the new protocol is the broom method.
我們需要一把新掃帚
We need a new broom.
我剛才真以為他死了
I for sure thought he was dead.
拜託
Come on.
這還是
It's still broke
你上次發脾氣時弄壞的 是的 我能看出來
from the last time you were in a mood. Yeah, I can see that.
波音又來電話了 亨利 打給議會 別找我
Boeing called again. Call Congress, Henry, not me.
我沒有他們的電話號碼
I don't have their number.
每天... 這裏都有東西壞掉
Every day, every day, something is breaking around here.
或者爆炸 我們資金不足 人手不足
Or blowing up. We're underfunded, under... understaffed.
但沒錯 他們還期望我們吊打蘇聯人
But yeah, we're still expected to beat the pants off the Russians.
你能告訴我到底該怎麼做到嗎?
You mind telling me how the hell we're supposed to do that?
就從善待自動售貨機開始吧
Could start by being a little nicer to the vending machines.
快看 在那裏
Ooh! There it is!
什麼? 有一隻貓
What? There's a cat.
那又怎麼了? 是一隻黑貓 亨利 代表霉運
So what? It's a black cat, Henry. It's bad luck.
好吧 不見了
Okay, it's gone.
好 謝天謝地 好吧 我們走
All right. Thank God. Okay. Let's go.
叫保安 不要
Call security. I won't.
我不叫 這... 你要去叫
I will not. It... Yes, you will.
我們這裏最不該出現的就是一隻黑貓
The last thing that we need around here is a black cat.
保安又不管這種事
They don't deal with things like this.
他們管的 現在管了
Yes, they do. They do now.
你反應過頭了 不 是你反應遲鈍
Y-You're overreacting. No, you're not overreacting enough.
立刻叫保安 馬上去
Call 'em right now. Right now.
我看起來如何?
How do I look?
容光煥發 加油
You're glowing. Good luck.
下午好 小伙子們
Good afternoon, boys.
走錯房間了 親愛的 我們不需要筆錄
Wrong room, sweetheart. We don't need dictation.
我叫凱莉·瓊斯 今天的會議由我主持
I'm Kelly Jones. I'll be running the meeting today.
你們一定是菲爾·亨利 尼爾·布朗和...
You must be Phil Hunley, Neil Brown and...
扎克·坦納 不介意我坐下吧?
Ooh. [chuckles] Zack Tanner. You don't mind if I sit down, do you?
恕我直言 瓊斯太太 我們是一家進步的公司
Uh, all due respect, Mrs. Jones, we're a progressive company.
我們的速記員團隊有16名女性
We employ 16 women in our steno pool.
我們向男人出售跑車 出售300馬力...
We're selling sports cars to men. We're selling a 300 horsepower...
355馬力 你們賣的是7014CC排量 V8引擎的猛獸
355, 428 cubic inch V-8 beast is what you're selling.
你們要著重推銷車的速度 比如這個
You want to focus on the car's speed. Something like this.
眼熟嗎? 雪佛蘭科邁羅 龐蒂亞克火鳥 還有奧斯莫比爾
Look familiar? Chevy Camaro. Pontiac Firebird. And Oldsmobile.
都是上個月的
All from last month.
幸好你們有些競爭對手沒有的東西
Thankfully, you have something that your competition doesn't have.
野馬Fastback 「給他355馬力 給家人安全帶」
The Mustang Fastback. "355 horses for him. Seat belts for the family."
安全帶? 我們安裝安全帶 只是因為明年可能會有強制安裝的規定
The seat belts? We only put them in because they might be mandatory next year.
我們來做個遊戲吧
Let's play a game.
我來猜你們幾位先生分別駕駛什麼車
Now I'm gonna guess what kind of car each one of you gentlemen drive.
扎克 1966年款福特野馬敞篷車 罌粟紅色的
Zack, Ford Mustang '66 convertible. It's poppy red.
不過你們當了老公的人不會開野馬 尼爾開林肯大陸
Oh, no Mustangs for you husbands though. A Lincoln Continental for Neil.
可憐的菲爾開客貨兩用車 菲爾 你知道我每天什麼時候最開心嗎?
A station wagon for poor Phil. Oh, Phil. You know what the best part of my day is?
是我老公查理晚上回家時
When my husband Charlie comes home at night.
我無法想像他有一天晚上不回家會怎樣
I can't even imagine what it would be like if-if one night he... he didn't.
你來想像一下這段對話
Now imagine the conversation
如果有人跟你老婆說這輛車
if someone told your wife that this car,
擁有355馬力和169公里的最高時速
its 355 horses and 105 top speed,
正是這輛車每天晚上 載著她老公安全回到家人身邊
this car is what brings her husband home safe to her family every night.
她希望你擁有這輛車
Now she wants you to have it.
她說出每個已婚男士夢想聽到的話
She says the words every married man dreams of hearing...
「如果你買下這輛野馬
"I'd feel so much better
我會感覺比現在更幸福 親愛的」
if you bought yourself that Mustang, sweetheart."
你怎麼猜到他們開什麼車的?
How did you guess what kind of cars they drive?
賄賂了他們的秘書還是怎樣?
What, bribe their secretaries or something?
凱莉 真的假的
Kelly, seriously?
兩包維珍妮牌女士香煙和一瓶帕科香水
Two packs of Virginia Slims and a bottle of Paco Rabanne.
每個人都是有價的
Everyone has their price.
幸好剛才我的羊水沒破 天啊
I'm just lucky that my water didn't break in there. Oh, God.
嗨 羅恩 你老婆好嗎?
Hi, Ron. How's the wife?
(創意總監 凱莉·瓊斯)
聽著 假肚子只能乾洗
Now, the baby bump, dry-clean only.
好的 我記下了 還有 歐米茄確認了下周的安排
Yes, I have that noted. A-Also, Omega confirmed for next week,
我完成了芭斯·羅繽的畫
I finished the Baskin-Robbins artwork,
Palmex那個人問你的地址 想給你送玫瑰
and that guy from Palmex asked for your address to send roses,
但我給了他我的 我知道
but I gave him mine because I know
你對玫瑰的看法 你知道我對玫瑰的看法
how you feel about roses. You know how I feel about roses.
還有 約翰又來電了 他想在星期二帶你去吃晚餐
Also, John called. Again. He wants to take you to dinner Tuesday.
告訴他我搬到洛杉磯去了 給陶氏化學的布魯斯打電話
Tell him I moved to LA. And call Bruce from Dow Chemical.
我聽說他們在給密保諾密封袋找新代理
I hear they're looking for a new agency for Ziploc.
人們應該抵制陶氏化學 他們做凝固汽油彈
People should be boycotting Dow. They make napalm.
人們嘴上說著抵制 但還是在買裝三文治的袋子
People say they're boycotting, but they're still buying sandwich bags.
他們還賣保鮮膜和泡沫塑料
They also sell Saran Wrap and Styrofoam.
你認為人們會停止使用泡沫塑料嗎? 你的咖啡用什麼裝的?
Think people are going to stop using Styrofoam? What's your coffee in?
聽著 我知道你和你的朋友們想拯救世界
Now, I know you and your friends want to save the world,
但等到你在1984年當上這裏的主管
and by the time you're running this place in 1984,
世上已經沒有核彈 全體人類平權了
there's gonna be no nukes and equal rights for all.
但在那之前 我們得幹好本職工作
But until then, we've got a job to do.
凱莉... 我們有大麻煩了
Kelly! Kelly! Kelly. Kelly. We've got a big problem.
我剛剛憤怒地離開片場 對 我有充分的理由
I just stormed off set, and, yes, it was justified.
我沒法跟胡佛這些人合作
I cannot work with these Hoover people.
顯然他們對我給他們拍廣告的方式有意見
Apparently, they have issues with the way that I am shooting their commercial.
他們真是這麼說的 「他們的」 那可是我的廣告
They actually said that. "Their." It's my commercial.
不就是做吸塵器的嘛 我可是搞藝術的
They make vacuums. I make art.
抱歉 我們約了見面嗎? 沒有...
Sorry, did we have a meeting set? No. No.
不好意思 我沒意識到還得約時間
I'm sorry. I didn't realize I had to set a time
才能跟最親愛的朋友說話
to speak to one of my dearest friends.
上次我們說話時你把我炒了 我現在不為你工作了
The last time we spoke, you fired me. And I don't work for you.
我跟你講 凱莉 我不是來聽你訓斥的
You know what, Kelly, I didn't come in here to be berated.
我是來找你支持我的
I came in to be agreed with!
你十分鐘後要向雀巢推銷 這很重要
You have that Nestle pitch in ten. Very important.
騙人的 再見
That is a lie. Goodbye.
蘭斯 給你拿到這份導演工作 堪稱聖誕奇跡
Lance, getting you this directing gig was a Christmas miracle.
你搞砸了那個果凍廣告拍攝後 我用了三周時間
It took me three weeks to convince them that you were stable
才說服他們你並非喜怒無常 果凍廣告那事不怪我
after your Jell-O shoot from hell. Jell-O was not my fault.
那個演員... 才五歲 你把他弄哭了
Ugh. That actor wa... Was five. You made him cry.
我是幫了那孩子一把 好萊塢可不好混
Well, I did that child a favor. Hollywood is no cakewalk.
那亨氏食品廣告呢? 你超了預算四萬塊 只是個番茄醬廣告而已
What about the Heinz commercial? You went 40,000 over budget. It was about ketchup.
才不是 重點是番茄醬帶來的希望
It was not about ketchup. It was about the promise of ketchup.
沒有人看到我在為他們的產品做什麼
No one sees what I'm doing for their products.
我在提升產品價值
I am elevating them.
我現在應該在拍電影了
I should be in film by now.
我拒絕了執導《娃娃谷》的機會
I passed on directing Valley of the Dolls.
那事怪我 但我還是該拍電影 好了 我們是怎麼稱呼你的?
That is on me, but still. Now, what do we call you, right?
廣告界的庫布裏克 好了 天啊 斯坦利是半吊子
The Kubrick of commercials. All right. Oh, my God. Stanley is a hack.
拍出一部好電影就突然成了天才
He does one good movie, and suddenly he's a genius.
你是傳奇 好嗎? 創意天才
You are a legend, right? Creative genius.
但你也脾氣暴躁 反覆無常 永遠不能按預算拍攝
You're also hotheaded, mercurial and can't stick to a budget for shit.
謝謝 這不是誇你
Oh, thank you. That wasn't a compliment.
這時就該當耳旁風 你若不跟胡佛合作 以後就沒人請你了
It is when you stop listening. If you quit Hoover, you'll be unhirable.
好吧
Okay.
蘭斯 不如你回片場吧
Lance, why don't you march your ass back to set,
不管發什麼脾氣 都道個歉 好嗎?
and you apologize for whatever fit you threw, okay?
給你男朋友買個棒棒的聖誕禮物 謝謝他容忍你
Buy your boyfriend something nice for Christmas for putting up with you.
也給我買個禮物 好嗎?
Get something for me too, okay?
聖誕快樂 蘭斯 聖誕快樂
Merry Christmas, Lance. Merry Christmas.
請你給我找份像樣的工作 好嗎?
Can you get me a decent job, please?
阿波羅8號於今早成功發射
Apollo 8 launched successfully this morning.
這場勝利是國家航空航天局的及時雨 在越南方面 今天有更多人犧牲
A much needed win for NASA. In Vietnam, more men were lost today.
(阿波羅8號發射錄影)
二千五百萬公里...
And 15 million miles...
麻煩再來一杯 另外把晚餐菜單拿給我
I'll have another round, please, and a look at the dinner menu.
好的 女士 謝謝
Yes, ma'am. Thanks.
今晚有兩個特色菜 雞肉餡餅和洛克菲勒牡蠣
Two specials tonight. Chicken potpie and Oysters Rockefeller.
我們吃雞好了 她對牡蠣過敏
We'll do the chicken. She's allergic to oysters.
給我來一杯麥卡倫 一個檸檬和一個砧板
And I'll take a shot of Macallan, a lemon and a cutting board.
好的 先生 不好意思 我認識你嗎?
Yes, sir. Oh, I'm sorry. Do I know you?
跑車上裝安全帶 這個點子很不錯
Seat belts in a sports car. I mean, that's a great angle.
很不幸 他們即將停止跟你合作
Unfortunately, they're about to kill the account.
為什麼?
Why would they do that?
因為有人告訴他們 你肚子裏其實沒孩子
Because someone told them that you don't really have a bun in the oven.
菲爾 讓我解釋一下
Phil. [chuckles] Let me explain.
我以後再也不會相信女人了
That's the last time I trust a woman.
我還給你送了一份嬰兒禮物
I actually sent you a baby gift.
你那麼做非常貼心 請讓我...
Which was so sweet, by the way. Let me just...
尼爾 讓我解釋一下 如果你們...
Neil, let-let me explain. If you...
怎麼回事? 你為誰工作? 奧美廣告?
What is this? Who do you work for, Ogilvy?
你業績拼不過我 就害我被解雇?
Huh? You can't outsell me, so you got me fired?
恰恰相反 我想聘請你
Just the opposite. I wanna hire you.
我叫莫·伯克斯 在總統辦公室工作
Name's Moe Berkus. I work for the president's office.
哪家公司的?
Of what company?
美國總統
The president.
我們需要一位營銷專家 聽說你是最厲害的
We need a, uh, marketing specialist, and word has it you are the very best.
於是我做了些調研 發現...
So I did a little digging, and, uh...
你的經歷很有趣 凱莉
You have quite a colorful past, Kelly.
還是說我該叫你簡? 來自芝加哥的空姐
Or should I call you Jane? Stewardess from Chicago.
也許你更喜歡被稱為艾米 俄亥俄州的護士
Or perhaps you would prefer Amy, the nurse from Ohio.
有這麼漂亮的臉蛋 誰還會看推薦信?
Face like that, who's gonna check references?
你找的那一頁不在這裏
Page you're looking for isn't in there.
我不知道你在說什麼
I don't know what you're talking about.
你當然不知道 我懂
Oh, sure you don't. And I get it.
嘿 我也有幾十個身份證 我的真名也不叫莫
Hey, I have dozens of IDs, and my real name's not Moe.
有那麼多名字可以選 你卻挑了「莫」?
With all the names you could've picked, you landed on Moe?
你天賦出眾
You have singular talent.
可以用來成就更偉大的事業 何必浪費在賣車上呢?
Why waste it selling cars when you can think bigger?
莫 有什麼公司比福特更偉大?
Well, Moe, what's bigger than Ford?
你去過佛羅里達州嗎?
You ever been to Florida?
他們想讓你推銷月球? 月球 阿波羅任務
They want you to sell the moon? The moon. The Apollo mission.
一整套
The whole thing.
這個叫莫的傢伙為國家航空航天局做事?
And this Moe guy works for NASA?
對 不 算是吧 他是政府的人
Yeah. I mean, y... Well, no. Um, kind of. He-He-He works for the government.
哪個部門?
Oh, which part?
凱莉
Kelly?
這個人... 我們在為理查德·尼克松工作?
Does this guy... Are we working for Richard Nixon?
因為我才不會為理查德·尼克松工作 凱莉
Because, Kelly, I will not work for Richard Nixon.
我是持證女權主義者 我真的有證
I'm a card-carrying feminist. I actually have a card.
我甚至不相信他要當總統了
I can't even believe he's going to be president.
我本來不知道自己對美國有這麼多意見
I had no idea I disagreed with this much of the country.
我們為國家航空航天局工作 推銷月球 沒人對月球有意見
We are working for NASA to sell the moon. Nobody disagrees about the moon.
不是 你我都清楚
No. You and I both know
我們身邊每天都有可怕的事發生
that everywhere around us every day something terrible is happening.
無所不在
Everywhere.
除了太空
Except in space.
真討厭 你說動我了 他們絕對需要我們的幫助
I hate that this is working on me. They definitely need our help.
你知道國家航空航天局的頭29次任務 只有48%的成功率嗎?
Did you know of NASA's first 29 missions, only 48% have been successful?
這不可能 太離譜了
That can't be. That's crazy.
你知道可可海灘市的 男女比例是五比一嗎? 天啊
Did you know the ratio of men to women in Cocoa Beach is 5-to-1? [chuckles] Wow.
只要你給我們找的住處不在兄弟會街就行
As long as you got us a quiet place that's not on Frat Row.
指南手冊說那裏很古雅
The... The guidebook said it's quaint.
(衛星汽車旅館 客滿)
你被炒魷魚了
You're fired.
這些都是什麼人啊?
Who are all these people?
今天星期三 他們好像在另一個星球上
It is a Wednesday. It's like they're on a different planet.
這裏叫佛羅里達
They call it Florida.
請告訴我你訂了一個遠離游泳池的房間
Please tell me you booked a room away from the pool.
16 21 天氣
sixteen and 21... Weather!
明天晴間多雲
Clear to partly cloudy tomorrow.
下午及傍晚 局部地區有雷陣雨
A few isolated thundershowers during the afternoon and early evening.
(佛羅里達州 可可海灘)
今晚最低氣溫18至24攝氏度
A low tonight, 65 to 75.
目前月球火箭發射場周邊城市 氣溫25攝氏度
Currently 77 in the Moonport cities.
這裏是KO2020電台 為你帶來的體育新聞和天氣預報
That's KO twenty-twenty news, sports and weather.
WKKO
WKKO...
(沃爾菲餐廳)
嗨 喬 晚上好 科爾 來點什麼?
Hey, Joe. Evening, Cole. What'll it be?
黑咖啡
Coffee. Black.
再來點最快能打包帶走的吃的 朋友
And whatever takes the least amount of time to put in a bag, my friend.
小姐 你很惹火
Uh, miss, you're on fire.
真有創意
Very original.
得了 我不想跟你玩乾柴烈火
No, I do not wanna stop, drop and roll with you.
不是 你的書著火了
No, your book is on fire.
天啊
God.
好 沒事的... 我的天
Okay. All right. All right. All right. Oh, my God.
抱歉 謝謝你 我只是... 教你個經驗法則
I'm sorry. Thank you. I just... Just as a rule of thumb,
酒精和火焰 絕配
alcohol and flames, they... they like each other.
是 天啊 我把你的外套燒壞了
Yeah. Oh, gosh. I-I-I ruined your jacket.
沒事 這衣服跟我出生入死
No, this thing's seen worse.
經歷過千錘百煉 請你喝一杯補償你吧
Been through worse. Let me buy a drink for your troubles.
不必了 必須的
That's not necessary. I insist.
我不喝酒 沒關係
I don't drink. It's okay.
真的? 不喝酒的宇航員 真有意思
Oh, really? An astronaut who doesn't drink. That's very intriguing.
你怎麼會認為我是宇航員?
What makes you think I'm an astronaut?
因為你戴著阿波羅胸針 只有宇航員才有
Because you have an Apollo pin, and only astronauts get those.
看來你對國家航空航天局略知一二
So you know a thing or two about NASA.
是 我是新晉粉絲 我叫凱莉·瓊斯
Yeah, well, I'm a recent fan. I'm Kelly Jones.
我不是宇航員 我只是在肯尼迪中心工作 科爾·戴維斯
I'm no astronaut. I just work at Kennedy. Cole Davis.
你做什麼工作?
Well, what do you do there?
聽著 我最不願意在閒聊中談工作
Uh... Look, the last thing I want to do is make small talk about my job. Oh.
抱歉 我不是那個意思
Sorry. That didn't sound...
我不是想... 沒關係 對 你只是實話實說
I didn't mean it for it to... Uh. That's okay. No. You were being honest.
你點的餐好了 科爾
Order up, Cole. Um...
我沒實話實說 如果我真的坦誠
I wasn't being honest. If I was being honest,
我會跟你說 你是我記憶中
I'd have told you you're the most beautiful woman
所見過最美的女人
that I've seen in longer than I can remember,
而我的記憶力很好
and I have a very good memory.
我只想請你喝一杯 然後跟你聊上幾小時
All I really want to do is just buy you a drink and talk to you for hours,
但我做不到 所以我要努力忘記你在這裏
but I can't so I'm trying really hard to just forget that you're here.
很高興認識你 凱莉
It was nice to meet you, Kelly.
非常抱歉
I really am sorry.
歡迎來到火箭路
Welcome to Rockets Road,
又稱鱷魚巷
also known as Alligator Alley.
如果想保住胳膊和腿
You'll wanna keep your arms and legs inside the cart
請不要把手腳伸出車外
if you wanna keep your arms and legs.
沒有啦 開個小玩笑 它們主要在水中發動攻擊
No, that's just a little joke. They mostly attack in the water.
(國家航空航天局 約翰F 肯尼迪航天中心)
好了 今天的參觀大約要兩個半到三小時
Now, today's tour will take approximately two and a half to three hours.
請舒適地坐好
So let's get comfy-cozy.
右手邊是我們的測試樓
Now on the right is our testing facility.
是世界頂尖水平的
State-of-the-art.
失火了 它經常失火
It's on fire. It is often on fire.
前方是載具組裝大樓
Up ahead, we have the vehicle assembly building.
是組裝火箭的地方
That's where they assemble the rockets.
是全世界最高的單層建築
That is the tallest single-story building in the world.
裏面能放下四座自由女神像
You can fit four Statue of Liberties inside that building.
天啊 《生活》雜誌 完全沒拍出它有多壯觀
Wow. Life Magazine really doesn't do it justice.
這也太... 我想進去看看
This is so gre... I'd love to go inside.
這裏嚴禁入內 抱歉 走 我們靠近點看看
It's highly restricted. I'm sorry. Come on, let's get a closer look.
不行... 這裏不得進入
Oh, no, no. No. There's no entry here.
你需要一個特殊的胸卡才能進
You need a special access badge to enter.
比如這個? 對
Oh, like... like this one?
那... 不行... 那是我的胸卡
Yeah. That's, uh... Oh, no, no, no, that's... that's my badge.
嘿 看看這地方 太大了
Uh, hey... Oh. Look at this place. It's enormous!
似乎大得多... 她們拿走了我的胸卡
It seems like it's much bigger... They took my badge!
看看這個建築
I mean, look at this building.
喂 那是我的胸卡 你好 先生 嗨
Hello? That's-That's my badge. Hello, sir. Hi.
我是國家航空航天局 公共事務部的凱莉·瓊斯
Kelly Jones from NASA Public Affairs.
這是我們倆的萬能通行證 謝謝
Here's our all-access pass for both of us. Thank you.
謝謝 等等... 我的胸卡
Thank you. Wait, wait. My card.
這個我能推銷出去
Now, this I can sell.
喲呼
Yoo-hoo!
你們好 小伙子們...
Hello. Boys, boys!
嗨 凱莉·瓊斯
Hi. Kelly Jones.
我是國家航空航天局 新成立的公共事務部的
I'm from the new NASA Public Affairs team.
我能問你們倆幾個問題嗎?
Can I ask you two a few questions?
姓名 年齡 你們在這裏的工作?
Name, age, and what's your job here?
我是斯圖·布萊斯 總工程師之一 24歲
Uh, I'm Stu Bryce. One of the, uh, head engineers, and I'm 24.
我們就說35歲 好
We'll say 35. Yeah.
你呢?
And you?
我叫唐·哈珀 我是他的手下 23歲
I'm Don Harper. I-I work for him, and I'm 23.
你們真年輕
You guys are babies.
國家航空航天局的平均年齡是26歲
The average age at NASA is 26.
但我們知道這裏也有些老年人
But w-we do know some old people that work here as well.
對 32 33歲的 是
Yeah, like, 32, 33. Yeah.
聽你們這麼說 我很想殺了你倆
I'll try not to kill both of you for saying that.
跟我們說說 斯圖 你為什麼加入這偉大的美國任務?
So, tell us, Stu, what brings you to join this great American mission?
我在大學宿舍里看到了一張傳單
Well, I s... saw a, uh, flyer in my college dorm.
「從小就熱愛群星」 很好
"A childhood love of the stars." That's good.
非常感人 非常好
That's very moving. That's very good.
你呢? 不好意思
And you? Excuse me?
你怎麼來了?
What are you doing here?
我特意來找你的 想給你我的電話號碼
Well, I... I tracked you down to give you my phone number,
因為我感覺我們很來電
'cause I felt we had a connection.
什麼? 別緊張 我開玩笑的
What? Relax. I'm joking.
我現在在這裏工作 莫·伯克斯招我進來 改組國家航空航天局公共事務部
I work here now. Moe Berkus brought me on to revamp NASA Public Affairs.
你就是來自曼哈頓的廣告精英
So you're the killer from Manhattan.
你一定就是發射主管 這是我的同事露比·馬丁
And you must be the launch director. This is my associate, Ruby Martin.
好 我不在乎 聽著 這棟樓完全禁止進入
Yeah, I don't care. Look. This building is completely off-limits.
這裏有各種可能燒傷 凍傷 烤焦
Everything in here can burn you, freeze you, fry you,
毒死 砸死你們的東西
poison you and crush you.
走吧 出去 你在這裏工作多久了?
So let's go. Out. How long have you worked here?
很長時間了
A substantial amount of time. Hmm.
你在寫什麼? 你的原話
What are you writing? Your quote.
這不算原話 我只是隨口一說
That's not a quote. It was just a thing that I said.
我會添油加醋的 你今天有時間接受採訪嗎?
I'll punch it up. Do you have time today for an interview?
我還需要跟你的上級談談
And also, I need to sit down with your senior officers.
上相的優先 我可以幫忙挑
The photogenic types first. I can help with the selection process.
聽著 我這裏的人都太奇怪了 不適合採訪
Look, my guys are too weird for interviews,
而且他們真的在忙生死攸關的工作
and they're actually busy doing life-and-death work.
好吧 我不需要你的批准
Well, you know, I don't need your permission.
美國人跟太空之間 漫長且昂貴的蜜月期已經結束
The Americans are over their long and expensive honeymoon in space,
我是來提醒大家當初為什麼愛上太空的
and I'm here to remind them why they fell in love in the first place.
是嗎? 美國人應該心存感激
Is that right? Well, Americans should be very grateful
這些人為了這項任務在冒生命危險
that these men are putting their lives on the line for the mission.
你並不怎麼瞭解美國人 是吧?
Well, you don't know much about American people, do you?
你也不怎麼瞭解 你的辦公室吧? 我帶你看看
You don't know very much about your office I'm about to show you, do you?
這是儲物間嗎?
Is this a storage closet?
不是 儲物間有窗戶
Nope. Storage closet has a window.
好 速溶咖啡在休息室
Okay, so, instant coffee... is in the break room.
記得先把水龍頭打開 放一分鐘的水 把鐵銹沖掉
Just run the tap for a minute to flush out the rust.
你們有誰會用滅火器嗎?
Do either of you know how to work a fire extinguisher?
不會? 好吧 四步口訣 很簡單
No? Mkay. PASS method's pretty simple.
拔安全銷 對準火焰 壓下把手 噴向火焰
Just, uh, pull the pin, aim, squeeze, sweep.
如果你們有任何其他需要
If you need anything else,
可以回紐約去拿 祝你們愉快
uh, maybe just go back to New York and get it. Have a good day.
至少他還算養眼 但說話很刺耳
Well, at least he's easy on the eyes. He's hard on the ears though.
歡迎儀式很爛啊 我以為你說他們想要我們幫忙呢
Not a great welcome wagon. I thought you said they wanted our help.
不 我說他們需要我們幫忙 這一點現在已經實錘到不能再實錘
Oh, no. I said they needed our help. And I do believe that now more than ever.
如果我們誰都不能談或什麼都不能看
How are we supposed to do that if we can't talk to anyone
那要怎麼幫忙?
or look at anything?
是一隻貓...
Aw, it's a cat. It's a cat.
是一隻貓 是一隻貓
It's a cat! It's a cat.
你知道關於黑貓的說法嗎?
You know what they say about black cats?
如果黑貓從你面前路過 可能是要去其他地方
If they cross your path, they're probably going someplace else.
好 該把舊名片夾翻出來了
Okay, time to dig out the old Rolodex.
創意時間到
Let's get creative.
阿波羅11號將把我們的人送上月球
Apollo 11 will land our men on the moon,
這會讓我們成為世界第一
and that makes us first.
如果我們完成工作 將會在那裏發射
If we do our jobs, we will launch right from there,
時間是7月16日一大早
July 16, bright and early.
在那之前
Between now and then,
我們要完成人類歷史上
we will piece together the biggest jigsaw puzzle
最大的拼圖
in the history of mankind.
六百萬個零部件散落在全國各地
Six million parts spread out around the country,
我們要對每一個零件 進行組裝 測試 再測試
and we will assemble, test, and retest every single one
直到我們確定阿波羅11號 可以萬無一失地發射
until we are certain that Apollo 11 will take off
並飛向月球 就在...
without a hitch and head to the moon in...
亨利 你說
Henry, sing it.
在七個月後
Seven months. Huh?
七個月後
Seven months.
請幫我恭喜阿波羅11號的宇航員
Please help me congratulate the astronauts of Apollo 11.
阿姆斯特朗 奧爾德林和柯林斯
Armstrong, Aldrin and Collins.
嘿... 夥計們 你們覺得白宮怎麼樣?
Hey, hey! How'd you like the White House, boys? Huh?
(月球 我們來了)
還不錯 只可惜尼爾不讓我偷那裏的瓷器
Yeah, it was all right, except Neil wouldn't let me steal the china.
好 因為在八個月後 等這一切都結束
All right. Because in eight months, when this is all over,
他們需要新歷史書 來記載我們在這裏取得的成就時
and they need new history books to cover what we've accomplished here,
你們每一個人都能說
each and every single one of you will be able to say that
「我做了有史以來最困難的事」 對嗎?
"I did the hardest thing that has ever been done." Yeah?
對
Yeah!
行動起來 開工
Let's do it. Let's get to it!
漂亮 說得好 謝謝
Beautiful. Perfect. Thank you.
是 長官
Yeah. Sir,
你說新來的女士 只要做任何你不喜歡的事就通知你
you said to tell you when the new lady did anything you wouldn't like.
我身處肯尼迪航天中心
I'm here at the Kennedy Space Center
有幸採訪到副發射主管亨利·斯莫爾斯
with Deputy Launch Director, Henry Smalls.
怎麼回事? 那是我的名字 他盜用了我的名字和職位
What's going on? That's my name. He's got my name and my job!
這段時間對我們所有人來說都很美好 對我來說更具個人感情
It's been a great time for all of us. You know, for me, this is very personal.
我父親是一位空軍士兵
My father was an airman...
這是誰啊?
Who is that?
反正不是我 他在服役時犧牲了
It's not me. he died in the line of duty
當時我還是個孩子 我沒那麼帥
when I was a child... I'm not that handsome.
這是為了你 老爸
... so this is for you, Dad.
真是夠了 聽到這個我很遺憾
Oh, that's it. So sorry to hear that.
謝謝你的分享 這一定很... 我爸還活著呢
Thanks for sharing. That must've been... My dad's still alive.
對 要怎樣才能約在晚上6點左右呢? 好
Right. What is it that we can do to sort of make 6:00 p.m.? Yeah.
國家航空航天局公共事務部 我是凱莉·瓊斯
NASA Public Affairs, this is Kelly Jones.
凱莉 美國廣播公司 想要下周的媒體錄影帶
Kelly, ABC wants next week's press reel.
還想要我們手上最好的阿波羅8號照片
They also want the best photo we have from the Apollo 8.
跟他們說 如果讓我們 上晚6點時間段就給他們
Tell them they can have it if they give us their 6:00 p.m. time slot.
明白 如果你們播放動畫片段
Got it. If you air an animated segment,
我能給你們提供獨家的... 非常感謝
I can offer you an exclusive... Thank you so much.
你父親是個英雄 你是個英雄 我們非常感激你勤懇地...
Your father was a hero. You are a hero. We so appreciate you working at...
那是全國廣播公司新聞主管 是 我不管 這人是誰?
That was the head of NBC News. Yeah, I don't care. Who is that?
謝謝 我們月球上見
Thank you. See you on the moon.
在公眾眼裏 他是亨利·斯莫爾斯
To the world, that's Henry Smalls.
他不是亨利·斯莫爾斯
That's not Henry Smalls.
對 但你跟我說你們不接受採訪
No, but you told me that your guys don't do interviews,
所以我只能另請新人
so I had to hire new guys.
你讓兩位全球最頂尖的工程師裝窗戶
You have two of the best engineers on the planet installing a window.
菲爾 你再揮一下錘子 我一定會瘋掉
Phil, if you hammer one more time, I swear to God I'm gonna lose my mind.
把錘子放下 摘掉該死的工具帶
Put down the hammer, take your stupid belts off
回去測試
and get back to testing.
動起來 走了
On the move. Here we go.
這景色絕了吧?
Can you believe that view?
我們拿到了阿波羅8號的第一批照片 比我的好
We got the first photos from Apollo 8. It's better than mine.
從月球拍的第一張地球照片
The first shot of the earth from the moon.
這是不是你見過最美的東西?
Isn't that the most beautiful thing you've ever seen?
你怎麼比我先拿到? 他們稱之為「地出」
How'd you get this before me? They're calling it "Earthrise."
這張照片會登上今晚所有新聞的頭條
It's going to be at the top of every news segment tonight.
1968年太糟糕了
I mean, '68 has been such a terrible year.
刺殺 可憎的戰爭 我們見證了人類最醜惡的一面
Assassinations, this heinous war, we've seen the worst of humanity.
這時國家航空航天局公佈這張照片 一個看世界的全新視角
Now NASA gives us this? A whole new way to see the world.
我會確保所有人都看到
And I'm gonna make sure everybody sees it.
你不能找人冒充別人啊
You can't just fake people!
嗨 我是來參加選角的
Hey, I'm here for the casting. Oh!
他是誰? 是你 你這個角色可搶手了
Who's he? You. You're a juicy part.
要拍這幾場戲 這裏是角色生平
So, here's the scenes and the character bio.
你要扮演的就是這位 所以最好提升一點魅力
This is the man that you're playing, so you wanna up the charisma a bit.
好 我會提升... 明白? 好
Can do. I'll up the... Okay? Okay.
在朝鮮執行過60次任務? 是的
Sixty missions in Korea? Yeah.
我很榮幸 我在朝鮮飛過52次任務
It's an honor. I flew 52 missions in Korea.
我取了個整數
I rounded up.
「我在朝鮮飛過52次任務」 怎麼樣?
"I flew 52 missions in Korea." How was that?
什麼? 我會練習一下的
What? I'll work on it.
她現在都找好人冒充我了
She has a fake me now.
她已經有了個假的我 她有個假的我 假的你
She got a fake me. She got a fake me and a fake you.
不能冒充你和我 一無所獲
You can't fake me and you. There's nothing here.
沒有莫·伯克斯 我每個字都看過了
There's no Moe Berkus. I checked every spelling.
有個叫莫·伯克斯的打來電話
I have a Moe Berkus on the line.
要我來說嗎? 不... 我會很享受的
Do you want me to talk? Oh, no, no. I'm gonna enjoy this.
這將是國家航空航天局史上最快速的解雇
This is gonna be the fastest firing in NASA's history.
嗨 莫 科爾 我聽說你在找我
Hey, Moe. Cole, I hear you're looking for me.
是的 凱莉·瓊斯 聘請了演員來假扮國家航空航天局工程師
I am. Kelly Jones hired actors to play NASA engineers.
這是不可接受的 我要她今天就走人
It is unacceptable. I want her desk cleared today.
冷靜點... 好嗎?
Calm, calm, calm down, okay?
華盛頓的政要們會看電視 阿波羅現在上電視了
Washington watches TV. Apollo is now on TV.
每個頻道 每天都播
Every channel, every day.
你們想登月嗎?
So, you want to get to the moon?
我建議你們專心做好本職工作
I suggest, focus on your job.
也讓凱莉做好本職工作
Let Kelly do hers.
如果她把你打造成舞會上的焦點
If she's made you the belle of the ball,
你不妨穿上芭蕾舞裙來跳一段
why don't you just slip on your tutu and do some dancing?
炒掉她了?
She fired? Mm-mmm.
我們被炒了?
Are we fired?
阿波羅8號載著宇航員 博爾曼 洛弗爾和安德斯
Apollo 8, carrying astronauts Borman, Lovell and Anders
由土星5號送入了太空
was launched into space by a Saturn V.
每一個電視網都在播放地出照片
Every single network is airing the Earthrise shot.
會傳遍世界各地
I mean, it's... it's gonna be everywhere.
我試著畫了幾筆
You know, I tried a little something on it,
但好像效果還不行 不夠吸引人 我們需要一個關聯
but I just don't think it's working yet. It's not enough. We need a hook,
一個把登月和人們日常生活掛鉤的方法
a way to weave the moon landing into people's everyday lives
還得潛移默化
without them realizing it.
嗨 你們有類似沙拉的東西嗎?
Uh, hi. Do you have anything close to a salad?
漢堡上的醃黃瓜
Pickles come on a burger.
不過要等一等 阿波羅的新聞一出 生意變好了
It's gonna be a minute, though. Apollo news has business picking up.
有很多遊客想來親眼見證歷史
All the tourists love to come in and see little pieces of history.
見證歷史? 對 比如那支筆
Pieces of history? Yeah, like... like that pen.
1961年 約翰·格倫每晚都來這裏用餐
John Glenn ate here every night in '61.
(沃爾菲上太空了)
他用我們的一支筆來寫飛行手冊
He would work on his flight manuals, and he'd use one of our pens.
那支筆上過水星6號
That one ended up on Mercury 6.
這裏是全世界唯一一家 名字上過太空的餐廳
You're at the only restaurant in the world whose name's been in space.
很酷
That's cool.
正前方
And right up ahead,
是著名的水星火箭
it's the famous Mercury rockets.
一定要在這裏拍照 但別站太近
Be sure to get a picture here, but don't stand too close.
火箭可能會發射
They might go off.
那個週末過後 他就恢復了
He recovered after that weekend.
(你能準備好嗎? 距離發射還有171天)
你每次進房間 大家都會安靜下來 你感到困擾嗎?
Does it bother you that a room dies every time you walk into it?
你該待在你那邊的
You're supposed to stay on your side.
我想你了
I missed you. Hmm.
我希望你批准我們新的推廣活動
I'd like you to approve our new ad campaigns.
你不如就像上次一樣先斬後奏吧
Why don't you just sidestep me like you did last time?
我想為那些讓你措手不及的採訪道歉
I wanna apologize for blindsiding you with the interviews.
我有辦法解決我們的資金問題
I have a fix for our money problems.
我不接受你的道歉 也不接受這些莫名奇妙的東西
Well, your apology is rejected, and so is whatever this is.
歐米茄 聽著 這裏不是麥迪遜大道
Omega. Look, this isn't Madison Avenue.
我們不會為這種東西買單 不 免費的
We don't pay for this stuff. No, it's cost-free.
品牌方能得到錢都買不到的合作機會
The brands get a tie-in money can't buy,
而國家航空航天局 可以潛移默化去影響普通人
and NASA works its way into the minds of everyday people.
手錶廣告? 這就是你的絕妙點子?
A watch ad? That's-That's your big idea?
準備好了?
Ready? Mm-hmm.
牙膏
Toothpaste.
果珍 「阿波羅宇航員選擇的 能量早餐飲品
Tang. "The energy breakfast drink chosen for Apollo astronauts
專供登月之旅使用」 月球優惠券?
on their trip to the moon." Moon coupons?
但我個人最喜歡的要屬這個
But, my personal favorite,
鮮果布衣 是吧?
Fruit of the Loom. Right?
宇航員在太空服裏面總得穿點什麼吧?
The guys gotta wear something under those big suits, don't they?
鮮果布衣真的太能代表航天局了
Nothing says NASA like Fruit of the Loom.
聽著 我不會把飛船變成飛行廣告牌
Look, I am not turning this ship into a flying billboard
無論你多麼渴望都不行
no matter how much you want it to happen.
還有 我們沒時間在發射前測試這些東西
And by the way, we don't have time to test all this before liftoff.
我們不必真的把這些送上太空 只要說說就好
We don't have to send any of this up into space as long as we say it went.
所以你打算撒謊?
Oh, so you're gonna lie?
這叫推銷 我們不會欺騙顧客
It's called selling. We're not lying to the customer.
我們在改變他們的思維方式 不 這叫撒謊
We're changing the way they think. No, it's called lying.
所有人在你眼裏都只是顧客嗎?
Everyone is just a customer to you, huh?
聽著 我知道你是個厲害的廣告精英
Look, I know that you're a big old fancy ad shark and everything,
但國家航空航天局 不是能用廣告曲和廣告詞推銷的
but NASA's not something that you sell with a jingle and a slogan.
你不知道我們是誰
You do not know who we are.
行 好吧 瑪格麗特·漢密爾頓是誰?
Yeah, okay. Who's Margaret Hamilton?
誰? 她是你的手下
Who? She works here for you.
有四十萬人和太空計劃有關
There are 400,000 people that are affiliated
瓊斯女士 她是你的工程師之一
with this space program, Ms. Jones. She's one of your engineers.
喬安·摩根是誰? 她是點火室的
Who's JoAnn Morgan? She works in the firing room.
你問過她當初為什麼接這份工作嗎? 我就問過
Did you ever ask her why she took this job in the first place? I have.
她說因為她的血液裏流的都是火箭燃料
She says it's because she has rocket fuel in her blood.
國家航空航天局不光是個標誌 也代表著人民
And NASA's not just a logo, it's people.
那些每天早上醒來
People who wake up every morning
決心創造奇跡的人
and commit to accomplishing the impossible.
同時跟大家穿著一樣的內衣
And all while wearing the same underwear as the rest of us.
艾拉 你有任何需要嗎?
Ella, can I help you with anything at all?
謝謝
Thank you.
我預估了一下 如果你接受關鍵贊助
So I ran the projections, and this is what you stand to make
能賺到這個數
if you accept key sponsorships.
我們不能收私人的錢
We-We can't take private money.
無所謂的 明白嗎?
It doesn't matter, okay?
我即將讓航天局變得非常受歡迎
I'm about to make NASA so popular
國會終將重新提供資金
that Congress will finally turn the taps back on around here.
我只需讓阿姆斯特朗 戴上一塊歐米茄手錶就行?
And all I have to do is just let Armstrong put on an Omega watch?
不 如果我們得到資金
No. If we get the money flowing,
那你必須向我證明
then you've gotta prove to me
可可海灘也有不錯的地方可以吃晚餐
that Cocoa Beach has a decent place to get dinner.
成交 我... 好 成交 太好了 嗚呼
Deal. I... Yes! Deal! Yes! Whoo!
不 等等 我得設置底線 手紙不行
Uh, no, wait. I'm drawing the line at toilet paper though,
因為世人不用知道我們的人用什麼擦屁股
because the world does not get to know what our guys wipe their ass with.
真臭
Well, shit.
你返回地球後想去度假嗎?
Would you like to go for a vacation when you come back to earth?
根據目前的情況看
The situation being what it is now,
我最可能去的地方...
the place I would most like to go, uh...
下次把桌子撤掉 沃爾特
Lose the table next time, Walter.
尼爾看起來 像在做通用電氣的季度盈利報告
Neil looks like he's giving GE's quarterly profit report.
我們一直用這張桌...
That's always been our table...
電視讓他們走進人們的起居室
TV brings them in to people's living rooms.
他們應該看起來像家中的客人
They should look like they belong there.
那意味著我們成功了
It'd mean that we succeeded.
你還是負責人 沃爾特 別擔心
You're still in charge, Walter. Don't you worry.
不過等我幫完忙後
When I'm done helping though,
這些人會比披頭士樂隊還火
those men are gonna be bigger than The Beatles.
我可以完成99.9%的登月之旅 我很滿意
I'm getting to go 99.9% of the way there, and that suits me just fine.
(下一站 月球)
(阿波羅11號 最危險的航行)
家樂氏的那個副總叫什麼? 應該是哈里森·德裏斯科爾
What's the name of that VP at Kellogg's? I believe it's Harrison Driscoll.
(阿波羅登月在即)
好 哈里森
All right, Harrison.
不要用「辟啪 笑笑 泡泡」 改用「尼爾 巴茲和邁克」 不錯吧?
So instead of "Snap, Crackle, Pop," "Neil, Buzz and Mike." It's cute, right?
科爾
Cole!
確保那個不會生銹 亨利 能簽一下這些嗎?
Make sure that doesn't rust, Henry. Can you mark these?
嘿... 你看見了嗎?
Hey, hey. Did you see that?
你沒看見那隻貓?
You didn't see the cat?
果珍的瓶子再推近些
Go closer on the Tang bottle.
字體再大些 放上培根和雞蛋
Make the font bigger and put bacon with the eggs.
別忘了 我們推銷的是美國
Let's not forget, we're selling America, here.
「彼得潘花生醬 絲滑到飛起 此醬只應天上有」
"Peter Pan Peanut Butter. Peanut butter that's out-of-this-world smooth."
「哈蘇 以他們的視角看世界」
"Hasselblad. See the world the way they do."
拉裏 這是歐米茄的好機會
Larry, this is Omega's big chance.
在每一塊超霸的背面 直到永遠
On the back of every Speedmaster till the end of time,
(宇航員登上月球時將佩戴歐米茄手錶)
「第一塊被戴上月球的手錶」 對吧?
"The first watch worn on the moon." Right?
現在我們得把它立起來
Now we just gotta stand her up.
一切都將是值得的
It's all gonna be worth it.
(美國靠阿波羅11號取得領先)
嘿... 你佔了我的車位 我們在為凱莉佈景
Hey. Hey! You're in my spot. We're setting up a shot for Kelly.
我們的阿波羅11號任務有三位宇航員
We've got three astronauts on the Apollo 11 mission.
他們站在三輛漂亮的美國汽車前
There they are in front of three beautiful American cars.
真棒
Oh, this is great.
你們必須立刻前往測試樓
You gotta be in the test facility right now.
跟凱莉說
Talk to Kelly.
凱莉說我們花1塊就能開走科爾維特
Kelly said we could take a Corvette home for a dollar.
你來啦 1美元?
There you are. A dollar?
我需要佔用他們15分鐘而已
I'm gonna need them for 15 minutes, but that's all.
我15分鐘前就需要他們了 凱莉
I needed them 15 minutes ago, Kelly.
你知道他們穿的宇航服有多貴嗎?
You know how expensive those suits are?
別擔心 他只是發射主管
Oh, don't worry. It's just the launch director.
登月艙的樣子很怪 凱利先生 它的原理是什麼?
This strange looking bird, the LEM, Mr. Kelly. How does it work?
這是讓人
Well, this is a spacecraft that's used
著陸到月球表面的飛船
to take men down to the lunar surface.
登月艙裏三位宇航員中的兩位...
And two of the three astronauts in the LEM...
飛行指揮 我們錯過了目標 正飄向廣袤的虛空
Flight, we missed target and are drifting into the vast abyss.
我們死了 再來 是
And we're dead. Again. Yeah.
著陸前30秒耗盡了燃料
Ran out of fuel 30 seconds before touchdown.
是 但是著陸本身不錯
Yeah, but the landing, though,
很順利 很好 俯仰角度很好 繼續
it was smooth... It was good. Great pitch. Forward.
你們倆撒謊的技術真爛
You're both bad liars.
尼爾 邁克 巴茲 能再為瓊斯女士 和歐米茄多拍一張照片嗎?
Neil, Mike, Buzz, if I can get one more photo for Ms. Jones and Omega?
哥們 你誰啊?
Who are you, man?
好 舉起手錶 小伙子們
All right, watches up, boys.
給歐米茄來個微笑
And smile for Omega.
我是戴維斯 我打擾到你了嗎?
Davis. Am I interrupting?
一直在打擾 你面前應該有個盒子
Always. There should be a box in front of you.
不如打開看看?
Why don't you open it?
歐米茄感謝你的服務
Omega thanks you for your service.
你的宇航員們在電視上大出風頭
Your boys are all over TV,
資金又開始流入了 所以... 共進晚餐?
the taps are flowing again. So... dinner?
好 卡納維拉爾碼頭 5點
Yeah. Canaveral Pier. Five o'clock.
戴著手錶來
Wear your watch.
下午3點是他們播放採訪的 最佳時段 也是最後一個
3:00 p.m. is their best and final time slot to air the interview.
播阿姆斯特朗的獨家採訪? 下午3點是給小孩和閒人看的
For an exclusive with Armstrong? 3:00 p.m. is for children and deadbeats.
他們說有戰爭方面的突發新聞
They said they have breaking news from the war.
敵軍規模未知
Unknown size enemy force.
敵軍傷亡人數不詳
Enemy casualties are unknown,
但大家都看到過到底是怎麼回事
but you've seen how it really was.
讓阿波羅任務一直有新聞的努力失敗了
So much for keeping Apollo back in the news cycle.
英雄主義 危險 恐懼 全部融為一體
Heroism, danger, fear, all rolled into one.
無法用語言形容
Words don't describe it.
我是哥倫比亞廣播公司新聞台的 理查德·思雷爾克德 柬埔寨邊境附近報道
Richard Threlkeld, CBS News. Near the Cambodian border.
謝謝你 斯科蒂船長 感謝
Thank you, Captain Scotty. Appreciate you.
好
Okay.
你對女士可真是一毛不拔
Well, you spare no expense on a lady.
嘗嘗看嘛
Just try it.
蝦 蛋黃醬 麵包
Shrimp, mayo, bun.
這恰好是方圓百里之內最美味的一餐
And that happens to be the best meal in a hundred miles.
我沒說錯吧
Mmm. Told you.
我怎麼不知道這地方?
How'd I not know about this place?
不是所有人都喜歡打廣告
Not everybody likes to advertise.
說得妙 有兩下子嘛
Nice one. That's good.
那是火箭發射的地方 就是那裏
That's where the rocket will launch out of. Right there.
你戴那塊手錶戴可真好看 你戴著很合適
That watch looks great on you. You wear it very well.
謝謝
Thanks.
那天晚上我在酒吧裏跟你說...
That night at the bar, what I said to you...
你的目光無法從我身上挪開
That you couldn't take your eyes off me,
我是你見過最美的女人
and I was the most beautiful woman that you'd ever seen?
對 就是這句 這... 對
Y-Yeah, that part. That... Yes. Mm-hmm.
是我衝動了
It was impulsive.
那是對陌生人說的話 可我們現在共事了
It was meant for a stranger, and we're working together now.
我只是不希望你認為我...
So, I just don't want you to think that I was...
對我有意思?
Interested?
我只是想把話說清楚
I just wanted to clear the air.
好的 說得很清楚
Oh. Well, the air was clear.
很好
Good.
我有個想法 對 那話只適用30秒
I had a thought. Yeah. It was perfect for 30 seconds.
有哪個電視網是全天候報道的?
What are the networks covering night and day?
你覺得我有時間看電視嗎?
You think I have time to watch TV?
越南 他們直接從前線報道
Vietnam. They're broadcasting straight from the action.
人們已經不想只聽新聞了
And people don't want to just hear the news anymore.
他們想直擊新聞現場
They wanna see it in the making.
好吧
Okay.
不妨就讓他們看
Why not let 'em?
(登月現場直播 阿波羅11號)
你想在登月艙裏放個電視直播攝像機?
Oh, you want to put a live television camera on the LEM?
是的
Yes.
我的人在太空裏努力活命
My guys are trying to survive up there.
沒時間學如何拍電影
They don't have time to figure out how to film a movie.
我們替他們學 他們只需對準目標拍攝即可
We'll figure it out for 'em. All they have to do is point and shoot.
你不明白 這是後勤方面的噩夢
You don't get it. It's a logistical nightmare.
問題涉及電力 儲存空間 重量
There's power issues, storage, weight.
甚至沒有攝像機能在太空裏工作
There's not even a camera that would work up there
因為夜晚溫度是零下129攝氏度 白天超過121攝氏度
'cause it's negative 200 degrees at night and over 250 degrees during the daytime.
你能想像看直播的情景嗎?
Can you imagine seeing it?
不能 我剛說了這不可能
No. I just said it's impossible.
對 這就是重點
Yes. That's the point. Mmm.
這將是有史以來最偉大的電視節目
It would be the greatest televised event ever.
你認為這是個綜藝節目嗎?
Do you think this is a game show?
蘇聯人沒有播出
There is a very good reason
他們在太空行走是有充分理由的
why the Soviets aren't broadcasting their space walks.
因為蘇聯是守口如瓶的獨裁政權國
Because they're a tight-lipped dictatorship.
對 我們不是 天啊
Yeah, that's not us. Wow.
我們取得成功 是舉國成功
When we succeed, we do it as a nation.
我們遭遇失敗 是舉國悲痛 對
And when we fail, we grieve as a nation. Right.
這就是作為美國人的意義所在
That's what it means to be American.
別跟我說作為美國人意味著什麼
Oh, stop telling me what it means to be an American.
我們當中只有一個人一輩子在報效祖國
There's only one of us here that has served their country their entire life.
抱歉 登月艙裏不會放攝像機的
I'm sorry. We're not putting the camera on the LEM.
我是認真的 不放
I mean it. We're not.
我們會放的
We are.
(壓力點)
沒有更多燃料 他不可能成功
There's no way he can do it without more fuel.
讓他再測一次 好
Have him run it again. Yeah.
好 我時間很緊 什麼事?
Okay. [sighs] I'm on a tight schedule. What is it?
凱莉跟我說了攝像機的點子 我們很喜歡
Kelly briefed me on the camera idea, and we like it.
非常喜歡
We like it a lot.
她說錯了 我們做不到
She misspoke. We can't do it.
根本沒有這種科技
There is no such technology that even exists.
其實有 你知道嗎?
Actually it does. You know?
這是國防部設計的
The Department of Defense designed this
為了夜間尋找在越南被擊落的飛行員
to find downed fighter pilots in Vietnam at night.
聽著 這是機密 但國防部會給你使用
Now, it's classified but the DOD is going to let you use it
只要沒人知道它是什麼即可
as long as nobody knows what it is.
絕對沒有空間裝這麼重的設備
There's absolutely no space for equipment that heavy.
老天 我們連螺絲釘都稱重
We are weighing screws for God's sake.
什麼... 這也就7公斤吧
What... I mean, what is this, 15 pounds?
好吧 那就用輕一些的螺絲釘
Okay. So, just, like, lighter screws.
我們在試用另一個燃料單元
We're trying for another fuel cell.
好讓我們的人登月後 依然有足夠的燃料發射
So our men, when they get to the moon, they still have enough fuel to lift off.
她所有的餿主意當中 這個是最糟糕的
Out of all her bad ideas, this one is the worst.
其實總統很喜歡這個點子
Actually, the president loves it.
所以現在這就是個好主意
So, now it's a great idea.
我跟你用簡單的話說吧 科爾
So, let me put it to you simply, Cole.
找個辦法把這東西放進那東西
Find a way to put this on that.
這是命令 頂頭老大下達的
This is an order. From the tippy top.
唐 斯圖 請到這裏來
Don, Stu. Can you come in here, please?
謝謝 別什麼事都鬧彆扭
Thank you. Let's not make everything so hard.
請幫瓊斯小姐把這個絕密攝像機拆出來
Please help Miss Jones strip this top secret camera down.
我不希望他們知道這是絕密
I don't want 'em to know it's top secret.
現在他們知道了
Well, now they do.
請把這個絕密攝像機拆出來
Please strip this top secret camera.
裝在登月艙上 以備直播
Mount it onto the LEM for live broadcasting.
科爾 還有一件事
Cole. One last thing.
上周 一架中情局的間諜飛機拍到幾張
Last week, a CIA spy plane took some surveillance photographs
蘇聯新型N1火箭的照片
of the new Russian N1 rocket.
國會看到了
And Congress saw it,
有些議員對最後一輪撥款
and some of the members are having cold feet
產生了疑慮
about the final round of funding.
我們還有好幾個月才能贏下登月競賽
We're months away from winning this thing.
我會讓他們來這裏參觀
I'm gonna send them down here,
你要說服他們稍安勿躁
and you're gonna convince them to sit tight.
不 我... 來寫幾個和他們談話的要點
No. I'm... I'm gonna write up some talking points.
別往心裏去
Don't take it personally.
飛行員和重力對抗 這是他們的天性
Pilots fight gravity. It's part of their nature.
亨利?
Henry?
我... 很高興你不是科爾
Well, I'm... I'm glad you're not Cole.
是
Oh? Yeah.
他不喜歡我吸煙
He don't like me smoking.
怎麼 你怕他會給你下禁足令?
What, are you worried he's gonna ground you?
不 我... 去年做了緊急搭橋手術
Uh, no. I, uh... I had emergency bypass surgery last year.
對 那個混蛋非常頑固 非要我活下去
Yeah. That son of a bitch. He's hell-bent on keeping me alive.
抱歉 我不知道
I'm sorry. I didn't know.
是 這裏沒人知道
Yeah. Nobody here does.
除了科爾
Just Cole.
對 他到醫院來 安慰了我太太三天
Yeah. He came to the hospital and held my wife's hand for three days.
是的 我們認識很久了
Yeah. It's a long way from the day we met.
當時那小子剛從朝鮮回來
Kid had just got back from Korea.
是空軍最優秀的飛行員
The top pilot in the Air Force.
銀星勳章 飛行十字勳章
Silver Star. Flying Cross.
他們當時選宇航員時 他在愛德華茲空軍基地是頭號人選
He was first in line at Edwards when they were looking for astronauts.
但他最後沒能入選
But, uh, he ended up not making the cut.
為什麼? 是他的脾氣吧
So, what got him? It was his temper.
不... 是他的心臟
No, no. His heart.
醫生發現他有心房顫動
Doc found an A-fib.
這個小毛病足以讓他無法參加太空計劃
A little thing but enough to keep him out of the program.
最優秀的飛行員科爾·戴維斯 卻永遠無法上太空
Cole Davis is the best pilot who will never get to space.
我在過去15年裏天天看這個景色
You know, I've been looking at this view every day for the last 15 years.
但最近我有種第一次看到的感覺
But lately, it's like I'm seeing it for the first time.
阿波羅1號給這裏留下了巨大的陰影
Apollo 1 cast a big shadow on this place.
重新看到一些光明真好
It's nice to have some light back.
好了
Okay.
嘿 我總看到科爾每天晚上開車去那邊
Hey, I keep seeing Cole drive out there every night.
他在做什麼?
What's he doing?
做園藝
Gardening.
(34號發射場)
(阿波羅1號乘組的精神永垂不朽)
準備好了嗎? 好了
You ready? Yeah.
好 聽著 我們... 帶參議員參觀一下
All right. Look, we just... We give the senator a tour.
我們好好哄他30分鐘 把這個地方運營下去
We play nice for 30 minutes. We keep the lights on.
好 行吧
Okay. Fine.
怎麼了? 它在那裏
What? She's just there.
別... 跑 不...
Don't run. No, no.
千萬別跑 別... 等等 閉嘴
Just don't run. Don't... Wait. [shushing] Shut up.
不 你看 你把它嚇跑了
No. See, you scared it.
我剛吃過東西
I just ate.
亨利 快...
Henry, come on! Come on!
我討厭那隻貓
I hate that cat.
我懂你的意思
I see what y... you mean.
這... 貓真討厭 你看到它看我的眼神了嗎?
That's an asshole cat. Did you see the look it gave me?
它在嘲諷我
It's just taunting me now.
這是什麼? 是貓食
What is that? That's cat food.
有人在餵它 是誰?
Somebody's feeding that thing. Who's doing that?
找出來 立刻查出是誰 立刻炒掉
Find them. [pants] Find them immediately, and fire them immediately.
戴維斯先生 長官 霍普參議員來了
Mr. Davis. Sir, uh, Senator Hopp is here.
好 怎麼了? 你看起來很帥
All right. What? You look fine.
參議員
Senator.
你好 戴維斯先生 參議員 我很榮幸
Hello, Mr. Davis. Senator. What an honor.
我很榮幸 幸會 先生 幸會
It's an honor and a pleasure. Very nice to see you.
阿波羅11號太空艙已經運達
Well, the Apollo 11 capsule has arrived,
下周 我們會把它裝在土星5號火箭上
and next week, we will be attaching it to the Saturn V rocket.
也就是發射升空 帶我們離開地球大氣層的那個火箭
And that gets us off the ground and out of earth's atmosphere.
這些都很了不起 但我得直說
Well, that's all very impressive, but I have to be up-front.
佐治亞州今年洪水氾濫
Georgia had some devastating floods this year.
我要投票把這筆錢用於賑災
And I'm voting to put this money toward our relief fund.
這似乎有點自私 不是嗎?
That seems a little selfish, don't you think?
你說什麼? 就是一種說法
Excuse me? Uh, that's a figure of speech.
他是這個意思 我的大多數投票人認為
Here's what he means. My voters mostly think
我們在登月計劃上花費過多
we are overspending on the moon.
有意思 因為當我... 喲呼
That's funny, because... Yoo-hoo!
不好意思 霍普參議員
Excuse me. Senator Hopp.
你可能不記得我了
Oh, you probably don't remember me,
但你在我大二時來我學校做過演講
but you spoke at my sophomore year of college.
佐治亞理工學院 1955級
Georgia Tech. '55.
你是個大黃蜂校友?
You're a Buzz?
是的 先生 我當然記得
Yes, sir. Of course I remember.
那天 你的話激勵了我
Your words inspired me that day.
你說「承諾意味著忠於一項事業」
You said, "Commitment means staying loyal to a cause."
兩年後 我以優異的成績畢業 現在我負責這個部門
Two years later, I graduated with honors. Now I run this department.
1962年 你曾說過 你無論如何
You know, in '62 you said that you would fight
都會為肯尼迪的夢想而奮鬥
for Kennedy's dream no matter what.
我知道登月任務在當時比現在受歡迎
I know that the moon mission was more popular back then,
但如果那個激勵我 在國家航空航天局工作的人
but it would be just a shame
沒能照當年的那些話去做
if the man whose words inspired me to work at NASA
就太可惜了
didn't live by those very same words.
那就太可惜了 不是嗎? 先生 你真是個了不起的人
It would be a shame, wouldn't it? Sir, you are just such a wonderful man.
非常感謝
Thank you so much. Mmm.
你真了不起
You are a wonderful man.
她可真是個佐治亞州甜心美女
Isn't she just a wonderful Georgia peach here?
天啊 是
Oh, my. Oh. Yes.
你嘴真甜 是的
You are so sweet. Yes, I am.
我帶你來一次貴賓級的參觀吧 這是他們的保密項目
Let me take you on the special VIP tour they didn't tell you about.
好啊 太好了
Oh, I'd love that. Wonderful.
你會陪我一起參觀嗎?
Do you go on this tour with me?
當然會
I absolutely will.
你真好
That's so sweet.
她都熱淚盈眶了 真嚇人
She teared up. I mean, it's scary.
揮手微笑
Wave and smile.
拜拜
Bye-bye!
太空計劃不光臃腫又混亂
The space program is not only a bloated mess,
阿波羅號還是對上帝
but Apollo flies in the face of our creator
和我國國父的不敬 我想提醒大家 我們不...
and the true father of this country. I would remind you that we don't...
我們搞定了霍普 還需要兩票 看起來不會是范寧了
We landed Hopp. We need two more votes. Looks like it's not gonna be Vanning.
絕對不是范寧 接下來是庫克參議員
Definitely not Vanning. Next, we have Senator Cook.
庫克有點嚇人 我實話實說
Cook's a little scary. I'm not gonna lie.
他是冷戰時期的保守派
He's a Cold War conservative.
他擔心我們的預算 會從國防部的武器研發經費裏出
He's worried that our budget takes away from weapons development at the DOD.
好 參議員 有了N1火箭
Now, Senator, with the N1 rocket,
蘇聯人還是有可能搶在我們前面登月
the Russians still could land on the moon before us.
我們接下來要向你展示的最新情報
What we're about to show you is our most recent intel
是他們登月後計劃建造的東西
on what they plan to build if they do.
這些是照片? 不是 先生
And these are photos? No, sir.
是概念畫 描繪可能的未來
Those are, uh, renderings of a possible future.
未來的照片?
Future photos?
那是個激光炮?
Is that a laser?
它正對著地球開火 先生
It's going towards earth, sir.
它叫什麼? 「要你命月球激光大殺器」 先生
What are they calling it? "Killer Lunar Laser Eliminator," sir.
「要你命月球激光大殺器」? 是 先生
"Killer Lunar Laser Eliminator"? Yes, sir.
見鬼 厲害了
Damn it. That's good.
最後還有赫奇斯參議員
And, finally, we have Senator Hedges.
他一直是阿波羅的粉絲
Now, he's always been a fan of Apollo,
但州政黨給他施壓 叫他不得撥款
but he's getting pressure from his state party not to fund.
他連呼吸都要對著媒體的鏡頭
He can't take in oxygen without a camera pointed at him,
那我們就去請點扛攝像機的朋友來
and we're about to have a few of those around here.
有什麼問題嗎?
Any questions?
沒有 女士
No, ma'am.
那我們去搞定他吧
Well, let's get him then.
大家好
Hello, everyone!
先生們
Gentlemen.
我... 很高興能故地重遊 各位
It's... It's... It's great to be back, everyone.
你們知道我有多喜歡阿波羅計劃
You know how much I love the Apollo program.
參議員 阿波羅10號只會繞月飛行
Senator. Apollo 10 will just be orbiting the moon.
但能給我們帶來 11號在月球著陸的關鍵信息
But it's gonna get us information critical for the touchdown of 11.
比如著陸條件和地點 了不起
Like landing conditions and location. Amazing.
我們為你準備了專座 參議員 在你的支持者中間
And we've a special seat for you here, Senator, amongst your fans.
為我嗎? 謝謝
For me? Oh. Thank you.
阿波羅發射控制中心 現在可以開始
Apollo launch control, and we are go on the countdown
阿波羅10號登月任務的倒計時了
for the Apollo 10 lunar mission at this time.
點火程序啟動
We have ignition sequence start.
五 四 三 二...
Five, four, three, two...
所有引擎啟動
All engines running.
發射 火箭升空
Liftoff. We have liftoff.
現在是整點後49分
Forty-nine minutes past the hour.
發射塔已分離...
Tower clear. Tower clear.
休斯敦 交給你了
Houston, she's all yours.
壯觀的發射 我都等不及回來看阿波羅11號了
Glorious launch. Can't wait to be right back here for Apollo 11.
我們非常感謝你的支持 參議員
We cannot thank you enough for your support, Senator.
有件事會麻煩你們一下
It's gonna cost you more than a pair of binoculars.
我欠老家做新聞的人一個人情
I owe a favor to the news fellas back home.
我希望你能接受他們的出鏡採訪
I'd like you to give them an on-camera interview.
參議員 我是最不適合出鏡的人了
Uh, Senator, I'm the very last person that you want in front of a camera.
我... 不接受採訪的
Uh, I d... I don't do interviews.
但為你可以破例 赫奇斯參議員 我們很樂意
Except for you, Senator Hedges. We would be delighted.
這女士很機智
Smart lady.
晚安 晚安
Good night. Good night.
凱莉
Kelly?
沒事的
It's okay.
一切盡在掌握
Got it all under control. Mm-hmm.
(好樣的 阿波羅)
嘿 嘿
Hey. Hey.
你也可以休息一晚的
You're entitled to a night off too, you know.
我若休息 那就是睡覺
If I am, it's to sleep.
你真的有家嗎?
Oh, you actually have a house?
我還以為你在辦公室睡呢
I thought you slept at the office.
對 通常是 但... 我有時和珍妮一起睡
Well, yeah. Usually. But, uh... Well, I mean, sometimes I sleep with Jenny.
好吧 是 她一定很棒
Oh, yeah. Right. Oh. I'm sure she's great.
珍妮嗎? 對 確實
Jenny? Yeah. She... She is.
想認識一下嗎?
You wanna meet her?
好啊 好 珍妮會喜歡你的 來
Yeah. Yeah. She'll love you. Come on.
珍妮 這是凱莉
Jenny. Jenny, uh, this is Kelly.
凱莉 這就是珍妮
Kelly, meet Jenny.
跟我戰爭中開的那架一樣
She's just like the one I flew in the war.
我把它放在這裏 方便在週末開出去兜兜風 省時間
Keep her here so I can get my flight hours on the weekends. Saves time.
很漂亮
She's quite a lady.
是的
Yeah. She is.
想飛一圈嗎? 不了
Wanna go up? No.
你確定? 確定
You sure? Yeah.
好 來吧
Okay. Come on.
我帶你看第二美的景色
Show you the second-best view.
看見那些深色的部分了嗎? 看見了
You see those dark parts there? Yeah.
我們稱之為「月海」
We call them the seas.
月海裏的重力更強一些 所以...
The gravity is stronger in the seas, so...
我們研究過在每一片月海裏著陸的情況
We've looked to land in, uh, pretty much every single one of them.
有澄海
You got the Sea of Serenity.
危海 我們很快便排除了這個
Sea of Crises. We crossed that one off the list pretty quick.
對 這個名字不利於宣傳
Yeah. That's bad PR.
我們最後決定在寧靜海著陸
And then we finally settled on, uh, the Sea of Tranquility.
那是最佳地點
That's the sweet spot.
這麼一想 我... 對月球的瞭解
You know, come to think about it, I... I know a lot more about the moon
遠遠超過我對你的瞭解
than I know about you by a long shot.
我甚至不知道你是哪裏人
I don't even know where you're from.
堪薩斯
Kansas.
來自堪薩斯的凱莉
Kelly from Kansas.
堪薩斯的凱莉 你是怎麼進入廣告這一行的?
How'd you get into advertising, Kelly from Kansas?
我爸爸離開時我四歲 媽媽失去了房子
Uh, well, I was four when my dad left, and my mom lost the house.
我們住在汽車裏
We lived in a car.
一個教堂給了她一份賣曲奇罐的工作
And... a church gave her a job selling cookie tins.
所以她想了個點子 如果由我挨家挨戶推銷就能賣出更多
So, she had this idea that we'd sell more if it was me going door-to-door.
是啊 聰明的女士
Oh, yeah. Smart lady.
曲奇罐 然後賣吸塵器 我長大些就轉而賣美容用品
Cookie tins, then it was vacuums, then beauty goods when I got older.
是的 我和我媽周遊全國
Yeah. Traveling the country, me and my mom.
我們的生活就是這樣重回正軌的
It's how we got back on our feet.
我很遺憾你不得不經歷這些
Well, I'm sorry you went through that.
不必 我...
Well, don't be. I...
對 我很小就學會了如何生存
Yeah. I learned early on how to survive.
而且家家都有本難念的經
Plus, we all have our share of tough breaks.
亨利跟我說了 心房顫動和你被計劃除名的事
Henry told me about the A-fib and you getting kicked out of the program.
我得去跟亨利聊聊
Hmm. I'm gonna have to have a little conversation with Henry.
不過我並不完全贊同你的說法
You know, I don't totally agree with you though.
怎麼講? 我就是不...
How's that? Well, I just don't...
我不認為我們的悲傷故事
I don't think that our sad stories are supposed to
就該教會我們如何在世上生存
teach us how to survive the world.
我認為它們應該激勵我們去改變世界
I think they're supposed to make us wanna change it.
科爾
Hmm. Cole!
巴茲正在試圖短路發動你的科邁羅
Buzz is trying to hot-wire your Camaro!
拜託 天啊
Come on, man.
那麼...
Well...
你最好去阻止他
You better go stop him.
是的
Yeah.
(衛星汽車旅館)
老天
Jesus!
我們得談談
We need to talk.
阿凱 你的工作做得十分出色
You have done outstanding work, Kel.
公眾的興趣大大提高了
Public interest is way up.
你搞定了參議員們 確保發射能順利進行
You landed the senators and secured the launch.
所以你就闖進我的旅店房間?
And that's why you broke into my motel room?
作為感謝嗎?
As a thank you?
現在我們知道全世界都會盯著我們看
Now that we know the whole world will be watching,
我們不容有失
we can't afford to lose.
我們必須準備好呈獻一個備用版本的
We need to be prepared to present an alternate version
登月任務
of the moon landing.
一個備用版本?
An alternate version?
阿爾忒彌斯版本
The... Artemis version.
她是阿波羅的孿生姐姐 也就是「備胎」
She was the twin sister of Apollo, uh, you know, the backup.
(絕密 阿爾忒彌斯計劃)
我們必須準備好拍一個小短片
So we just need to be ready to shoot a little picture.
向人們展示宇航員在月球上行走
Something showing us, you know, up there walking around,
朝鏡頭揮手
waving at the camera.
你是說作假? 如果一切順利 短片永遠也用不上
You mean, to fake it? All goes well, we never use it.
但萬一...
But if not...
你知道我為什麼從沒坐過牢嗎?
You know why I never went to prison?
大概知道 但你說吧
Probably, but humor me.
因為我見好就收
'Cause I quit while I'm ahead.
這麼大的事沒法保密 這裏有成千上萬的員工
Can't keep a secret this big. Thousands of people work here.
也有成千上萬人 在一個沙漠中的保密地點工作
Well, thousands of people work at a classified location in the desert
他們在對一個外星飛行器艦隊做實驗
that experiments on a fleet of extraterrestrial pods
是我們從海底撈上來的
that we found at the bottom of the ocean.
你從來沒聽說過吧?
And you never heard about that, did ya?
拜託 沒這回事
Come on, that's not true.
也許沒有 也許有
Uh, maybe it is, maybe it isn't.
但有一件事是可以肯定的
But the one thing you can be sure of
全世界都將看到美國人 在月球上插上美國國旗
is that the world will watch Americans plant an American flag on the moon.
你是說尼克松總統支持這麼干?
And you are telling me that President Nixon supports this?
可能會 他還不知情
He probably would. He doesn't know about it
同樣 科爾·戴維斯也會永遠蒙在鼓裏
in the same way that Cole Davis will never know about it.
這應該不是個問題
And that shouldn't be a problem
畢竟雖然你們越走越近
considering what else you haven't shared with him
但你還是有些事瞞著他
while you've grown closer.
那麼帥氣的一個人會怎麼想...
I mean, what would a clean-cut guy like that think about...
你已經說得很清楚了
You made your point.
誰也擺脫不了自己的過往
No one can outrun their past.
但我可以永遠抹除一個人的黑歷史
But I can make it go away. Forever.
不必再逃亡
No more running.
我得需要助理幫忙
I'm gonna need my assistant.
當然
Of course.
我們會給你配一個安全特工團隊
And we'll get you a team of secure agents.
好了 你手裏最厲害 但卻沒人聽說過的導演是誰?
Now, who's the best director you've got that no one's ever heard of?
你會喜歡他的
You're gonna love him.
(政府財產 非請莫入)
這是基地裏最偏遠的飛機庫
This is the most remote hangar on the base.
沒有我的允許 任何人不得出入
No one can go in or out without my permission.
等等 任何人? 連科爾都不行?
Wait, no one? Not even Cole?
科爾尤其不行
Especially not Cole.
難以置信 凱莉
Unbelievable, Kelly.
你找人強行把我拖上飛機
You have me... forced onto a plane,
把我帶到這該死的佛羅里達
and brought to godforsaken Florida!
能鬆手嗎?
Do you mind?
我是美國導演工會成員
I'm a member of the DGA.
不能被這樣粗暴對待
I will not be treated this way.
我要給經紀人打電話 不行
I am calling my agent. You can't.
我這就打給你看
Watch me.
記住 我們談過的 這是安保級別很高的政府項目
Remember we talked about this. This is a high-security government job.
我給你的報價翻倍 好吧
I'm doubling your quote. Okay.
還有獎金
With a bonus. Mmm.
對 唯一的條件是不能讓任何人知道 我們在幹什麼
Yes. The only caveat being that no one can ever know what we're doing.
這我無法接受 他們會槍斃你
I cannot accept that. They will shoot you.
預算是多少?
What is my budget?
你花多少錢都行 只要把這裏變成月球
Your budget is whatever it costs to turn this into the moon
拍出兩個半小時的片子來
for two-and-a-half hours.
比《賓虛》短
It's shorter than Ben-Hur.
我需要在那邊擺一台裝滿汽水的冰箱
I will need a fridge full of Tab over there.
和一大群不會提問的手下
And an army of minions who don't ask questions.
凱莉 這些都不是真正的演員
Kelly, these aren't real actors.
你只能用他們 這是最好的情況了
Well, this is the best you're gonna get.
尼爾身高1.8米 誰是1.8米高?
Neil's 5'11 ". Anybody 5'11"?
好 其他人散了吧
Okay. The rest of you are dismissed.
選吧 等等 你
Take your pick. Mmm. Hold on. You.
你來做我的私人助理
You're gonna be my personal assistant.
我就叫你約瑟夫 這樣有什麼事你不會往心裏去
I'll just call you Joseph so you can't take things personally.
隨便站一邊去吧
Go stand somewhere.
好 能把墨鏡都摘了嗎?
All right. Can we take these sunglasses off, please,
好讓我看到你們的眼睛 相信你們的話
so I can see your eyes and believe your truth?
好 我要每個人來一段獨白
Now, I want each of you to do a monologue.
最好是經典橋段 但是老天啊
Preferably something classical, and by God,
千萬別給我來七遍《哈姆雷特》
don't make me watch seven Hamlets.
你到時候看不見他們的臉 都戴著頭盔呢
You're not gonna see their faces. They're wearing helmets.
什...
Wh...
好吧 那我如何
All right, how do I convey
在不讓觀眾看到人臉的情況下
the gripping fear of being on the moon for the first time
展示第一次登月那揪心的恐懼?
if we can't show a human face?
表演是一種運動 凱莉
Acting is a sport, Kelly.
需要能量 身體... 我把設備放哪?
It is energy, body, bu... Where do I set up?
愛德華?
Edvard? Ah.
你怎麼進來的? 從門口走進來的
How did you get in here? I just walked through the door.
「此事說出去會害我們被殺」 這句話你哪兒不明白?
What part of "talking about this is gonna get us killed" do you not understand?
而且他是紐約動作最慢的攝影指導 我來選攝影師
And he's the slowest DP in New York. I pick the cinematographer.
寫在合同里呢 什麼? 你沒有合同
It's in my contract. What? You don't have a contract.
他最棒 所有的攝影指導動作都慢
He's the best, and all DPs are slow.
凱莉 我們最需要的
What we need to have a serious conversation about, Kelly,
就是美術指導
is production design, hmm?
我們用什麼材料來仿造月球表面?
What materials are we using to recreate the lunar surface?
月球就是塊大石頭 對吧?
It's just a big rock, right?
我沒法這樣工作 凱莉
I can't work like this, Kelly.
你是瞭解我這一點的
You know this about me. Hmm?
我需要細節
I need details.
我們需要細節 具體細節
We need details. Specifics.
是多塵 多石還是有風? 光源是怎樣的?
Is it dusty, rocky, windy? What is the light source? Hmm?
就是太陽咯 大燈 別自作聰明 愛德華
It's the sun. Big light. Do not smart-mouth me, Edvard.
太陽和著陸區的位置關係是怎樣的?
And what is the sun's position in relation to the landing area?
我們要建一個仿製版嗎? 我們有計劃嗎?
And are we building a replica? Do we have a plan?
我們有宇航服嗎? 演員穿上宇航服如何行動?
Do we have suits, and how do people move in those suits?
還有 凱莉 太空裏到底什麼樣子?
And what, Kelly, does space even look like?
我... 得躺一下
You know, I gotta... I gotta lie down.
我的拖車呢?
Where is my trailer?
我們得想辦法 把那個模擬室裏的一切都照搬過來
We need to find a way to copy everything in that simulation room.
好的 盡快
Okay. ASAP.
等等 我有拖車嗎?
Wait a second. Do I even have a trailer?
你不說話我也知道
Your silence tells me what I already know.
你還沒想過怎樣復刻月球
You haven't thought about how to recreate the moon,
怎麼會想拖車的事? 我覺得我們該找庫布裏克了
why would you think about a trailer? I think we should've gotten Kubrick.
我們必須把新的飛船做對了
We've got to get this new ship right.
阿姆斯特朗很生氣
I mean, Armstrong, he was pissed off
我們不能再惹他了 抱歉
and we can't have that again. Sorry.
夥計...
Buddy, buddy.
等等... 這些都是敏感材料
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. This is sensitive material.
亨利... 不行 你不能待在這裏
Henry. Henry. Uh-uh. You can't be here.
這些照片是為了企鵝出版社的檔案書拍的
These photos are for the archival book that Penguin is doing.
什麼書? 對 你沒收到備忘錄?
What book? Yeah, didn't you get the memo?
沒有 什麼? 你要寫前言
No. What? You're writing the foreword.
我... 寫前言? 對 是啊
I... I'm writing the foreword? Yeah, absolutely.
我? 沒錯
Me? Yes, of course.
我從沒寫過前言 編輯想聽聽你的話
I've never written a foreword. The editor wants to hear from you.
我們都想 他要我寫?
We all do. He wants me to write it?
別這麼謙虛好嗎? 我們給你拍一張和...
Don't be so humble, all right? Let's get a photo of you with the...
登月艙的合影 我可以寫 但...
with the LEM. I mean, I can do it, but...
說「我們要登月了」
Say, "we're going to the moon."
我們要登月了 真不錯
We're going to the moon. There you go!
奧爾德林和阿姆斯特朗 每一個動作都要練習
Aldrin and Armstrong will practice every single movement that they make,
在這裏練好幾個月
um, right here for months.
真了不起 是
That is incredible. Yeah.
這就是月球表面?
So, this is, like, the surface of the moon?
是 這... 對
Well, yeah. It's... Yeah.
是我們最接近的模擬
It's our best approximation.
這看起來就像個骯髒的海灘 我不信 不可能
This just looks like a dirty beach. I don't believe it. No.
是按... 我們得到的沉積物做的 約瑟夫
It is... It's based off sediment we got. Joseph.
來自航天局
It's from NASA...
等等 我不相信這就是國家航空航天局
Wait. I do not believe this is what NASA uses
用來登月的裝備 你別告訴我... 不行
to go to the moon. You cannot tell me... No.
我要你們假裝抱著母親在沙漠裏行走
Want you to walk as if you're carrying your mother across the desert.
她很脆弱 但也很重
She's frail but also heavy.
等等 嘿
Oh. Whoa. Hey.
真抱歉 嘿 對不起 不能拍...
So sorry. Hey. Sorry. Oh, no, no. No.
這是機密 你不能... 斯圖 沒事
This is classified. You're not allow... Stu, we're good.
是機密 沒事 這是為那本書拍的
Very classified. We're good here. This is for the book.
你會聽說的
No, you'll hear about it.
我要寫前言
I'm doing the foreword,
你很快會聽說的 好吧
so you'll hear about it soon. Okay.
我這個阿姆斯特朗是個總愛抱怨的爛人 我們得重新選角
My Armstrong is a whiny, little bitch. We have to recast.
不 我們不重新選角
No... We're not recasting.
好吧 那就平庸著拍吧
All right. Well, mediocre it is.
愛德華 我的太陽呢?
Edvard! Where is my sun?
很好
Nice!
非常好 至少來個倒數啊
Very nice. A countdown at least.
好 再開一次
Okay. Try it again.
我再開一次 從三倒數
Gonna try it again. Do a three, two, one!
拜託 滿意嗎?
Come on! Ah! Happy?
約瑟夫 給我拿汽水來
J... Joseph, bring me my Tab.
你得來找我 因為我眼都瞎了
You're gonna have to find me 'cause I can't see a thing.
拜託 拿個汽水要多久?
Come on. How long does it take to give someone a Tab?
我的手就在這裏
My hand's right here.
一定會很棒的 你們都該聚過來
Uh, this will be great. You guys should all come around
我們來給那本書拍一張 很好吧?
and we'll do a shot for the book. Great?
嘿 各位 這麼說如何? 「我們要登月了」
Hey, how about this? Everybody, "We're going to the moon!"
我們要登月了
We're going to the moon!
我好像眨眼了 再拍一張?
My eyes might have been closed. You wanna do one more?
最近沒看到你
I haven't seen you around lately.
彼此彼此
Well, I can say the same thing about you.
你怎麼一次就繫好了?
How do you do it on the first try?
這又不是多複雜的事 好 準備好了嗎?
It's not rocket science. Okay. You good?
那些問題 我... 是的
About the questions, I... Yes.
我都看過了 沒有關於阿波羅1號的 他們答應過我 好嗎?
I went over them. Nothing about Apollo 1. They promised me. Okay?
你會表現得很好的 明白嗎?
You're gonna be great. Okay?
去吧
Mm-hmm. Go on.
好 上
Okay. Go.
戴維斯先生 你是我們口中的「採訪困難戶」
Mr. Davis. You are what we call "a tough get."
哪有 謝謝
Ha! No. Thank you.
我們將看到尼爾阿姆斯特朗 和巴茲奧爾德林走上月球表面
Is there any legal importance to what we'll be watching
這有什麼法律方面的重要意義嗎?
when Neil Armstrong and Buzz Aldrin walk on the lunar surface?
他們著陸的區域會被視為歸美國所有嗎?
Will the area they land on be considered property of the United States?
我們要送一塊匾上去 寫著「我們為全人類的和平而來」
We're sending a plaque that says, "We came in peace for all mankind."
那正是我們的意思
And that is precisely what we mean.
國家航空航天局還會留下其他什麼東西?
What else will NASA leave behind?
足跡 一面美國國旗和12袋糞便
Footprints, an American flag and 12 bags of feces
他們跟我說了很多次不要提 但是...
that I was told many times that I should not bring up, but...
我們真該早點讓他接受採訪
Should've put him in front of a camera sooner.
你戴著一枚阿波羅胸針
You wear an Apollo pin.
是的
I do. Um,
是阿波羅1號乘組的太太們
the wives of Apollo 1's men,
在丈夫們犧牲後送我的
after we lost them, they gave me this.
在那悲劇的一天 你是發射主管
You were launch director on that tragic day.
阿波羅1號出了什麼故障?
What went wrong with Apollo 1?
用你自己的話說 發生了什麼?
In your own words, what happened?
幫我回顧一下
Take me back.
好 我來給你列舉一些事實
Okay. Here's some facts for you.
《紐約時報》報道
The New York Times reported
那艘飛船曾有兩萬份安全事件報告
there were 20,000 safety reports filed about that ship.
實在太多 以至於加斯·格裏森 用一個檸檬表示自己的不滿
So many, that Gus Grissom hung a lemon outside it.
好了 乘組 待確認 位置
All right, crew. To be confirmed. Location.
著火了
Flame!
駕駛艙裏失火了
We've got a fire in the cockpit.
快出去
Let's get out!
戴維斯先生 你讀過那些報告嗎?
Mr. Davis? Did you read those reports?
發射台主管 快進去救他們
Pad leader, get in there and help 'em.
發射台主管 盯著C3
Pad leader, stay on C3.
戴維斯先生 你讀過那些報告嗎?
Mr. Davis? Did you read those reports?
你讀過那些報告嗎? 我當然讀過那些報告
Did you read those reports? Of course I read the reports.
每一份都讀過
I read every single one of them.
獨立供電測試期間 氧氣壓力過高的同時遇到了線路故障
Overpressured oxygen and a bad wire on a "plugs-out" test.
我本該查出一切問題的 我看漏了 辜負了他們
I was supposed to catch everything, and I missed it. And I failed them.
我餘生中的每一天都會為此感到愧疚
And I will live with that every single day for the rest of my life.
人渣 這是你想引述的原話嗎?
Is that the quote that you were looking for, you piece of shit?
讓我跟你的老闆通話 立刻 馬上
Get me on the phone with your boss. Now. Now!
等等 你幹什麼? 採訪還有20分鐘
Oh, uh, wait. W-What are you doing? We have another 20 minutes.
去死吧
Go to hell.
別生我的氣 害死三個宇航員的人不是我
Don't be angry with me. I'm not the reason three astronauts are dead.
你再提一句那些宇航員試試 嘿... 別衝動
Say one more thing about the astronauts. Hey, hey, hey! Whoa!
放開我 你再說一句試試
Get off me. Let me hear you say one more thing...
你再提他們一句試試
Let me hear you say one more thing about them!
你不認識他們 你不准再提他們
You don't know those men! You don't talk about those men!
放開我 放開
Get off me! Get off!
放開
Get off!
聽懂了嗎?
Do you understand me?
我跟製作人們談過了 他們同意不播出這段採訪
So, I spoke to the producers, and they've agreed to seal the film
條件是阿姆斯特朗著陸後 給他們獨家採訪
if we give them the exclusive with Armstrong after he lands.
不過我們失去了赫奇斯的支持 他要投反對票了
We lost Hedges though. He's voting no.
你說過他們不會問的 是的 他們撒謊了
You said they wouldn't ask about it. Yeah. Well... they lied.
人們有時是會撒謊的 科爾
You know, people do that sometimes, Cole.
你也許可以說點假話 那也算為自己
You could have done yourself and this program a favor
和這登月計劃幫了個忙 對嗎?
and maybe tried it yourself. Right?
責怪國家航空航天局
Blame NASA.
責怪這個體系
Blame the system.
事關價值五億美元的資金啊
I mean, there was half a billion dollars worth of funding on the line.
撒謊對你來說一定輕而易舉吧 畢竟你總在撒謊
Lying must be so easy for you when you do it all the time.
撒謊總是一個可選項
It's just always an option.
你該試試說真話 你裝什麼清高呢?
What you should try is the truth. What is this sanctimonious bullshit?
我永遠不會就那些人或那一天的事撒謊
I'm never going to lie about those men or that day.
你明白嗎?
Do you understand that?
隨便你怎麼看我
You think what you want about me,
但因為不冷靜 而讓全人類登月夢破碎的人不是我
but I didn't cost the world a dream because I lost my goddamn cool.
這是34號發射場 發生阿波羅1號悲劇的地方
This is Launch Complex 34, where the Apollo 1 tragedy occurred.
這是犧牲英雄的紀念碑
This is a tribute to our fallen heroes,
這些勇敢的人為我們的成功鋪平了道路
the brave men who paved the road to our success.
請大家為他們默哀片刻
Please, let's take a moment of silence for them.
愛德華 真令人稱奇
Edvard, that looks incredible.
我完全看不到線纜 你怎麼做到的?
I can't see the wires at all. How did you do that?
我只是用了一塊遮光板 很簡單
I just put a flag. It's very simple.
老辦法了
Old school. Huh.
不行 從頭再來
No. Again. From the top.
這次多加一些跳躍
And maybe let's get some more bounce this time.
你們可是在月球上啊
You are on the moon.
好
Good.
天啊 我看不下去了 今天不行
Oh, my God. I-I can't. I can't with this day.
天啊 好 堅持住 約瑟夫 失火了
Oh, dear. Uh... Okay, hold on. Joseph, there's a fire.
我來
I got it.
別忘記四步口訣
Don't forget to PASS.
好 能放他們下來嗎? 算了 掛著吧
Okay. Can you bring them down? Actually, leave them up.
讓他們反思一下自己都幹了什麼
Let them think about what they did.
我放棄了 我去吃午飯
I give up. I'm taking lunch.
你們明白自己幹了什麼嗎? 你們讓她提早去吃午飯了
You see what you did? You made her take lunch early.
這都怪你們
That's on you.
我跟你賭5美元 你不擅長道歉
I'll bet you $5 you're bad at apologies.
我到處找你
I've been looking all over for you.
你欠我5塊 我有個想法
You owe me five bucks. I got an idea.
什麼?
What?
來 去路易斯安那州的路上告訴你
Come on. I'll tell you on the way to Louisiana.
不 你想嘗試獲得范寧的投票?
No. You wanna take a shot at Vanning?
我給咱們弄到了晚餐邀請 就是今晚 走吧
I got us a dinner invite, for tonight. Come on.
今晚? 我們不可能趕得上 有800公里呢
Tonight? We're never gonna make it. It's 500 miles away.
我們能趕上 來 你得相信我
We're gonna make it. Come on. You gotta trust me.
等等 不
Oh, wait. No.
不行... 什麼叫「不行」?
No, no, no. What do you mean, "no"?
我們不能... 有其他... 我們可以... 你想不想要范寧支持?
We don't... There's other... We could... Do you want Vanning or not?
我不... 來 我們走
Ugh. No. I don't... Come on. Let's go.
我覺得我們可以乘民航 如果我們出發...
I think we could just take a commercial flight. If we left...
不行 現在沒有民航航班
Nope. No commercial flights are flying right now.
來 跳上來
Come on. Just hop on in.
就是這樣 你只管上來就行 你可以跳上來的 你行的
This is it. This is all you gotta do. You can hop up, you can get in.
腳踩那裏 好吧 拿著我的鞋
Put your foot there. Okay, well, take these.
聽著 我們得走了 好
Look, we gotta go. All right.
等等...
Hold on. Hold on.
完美
Perfect.
等等 沒問題
Hold on. We're good.
風景不錯吧?
You enjoying the view?
天啊 太美了
Wow! It's stunning!
我打賭你閉著眼呢
I bet your eyes are closed.
沒有
No.
我猜你還會些其他南方口音
So, I'm betting you have some other Southern accents
畢竟你「多才多藝」 會路易斯安那的嗎?
in that bag of tricks of yours. Can you do Louisiana?
會 新奧爾良還是巴吞魯日?
Yeah. New Orleans or Baton Rouge?
用他老婆家鄉的 好
Wherever his wife's from. Okay.
科爾·戴維斯
Cole Davis.
你一定是凱莉·瓊斯小姐
And you must be Miss Kelly Jones.
兩位請進
Please come in, y'all. Oh.
非常感謝你們邀請我們吃晚餐
Thank you so much for having us for dinner.
好... 我聽說你是紐約城裏人
Oh, now... now, I was told you were a New York City type.
天啊 不是 我只是在那裏工作 我是路易斯安那人
Oh, God, no. I just work there. I'm from Louisiana.
土生土長的 也會落葉歸根
Born and raised and, one day, buried.
我老家在弗吉尼亞 不會吧? 我們是親人啊
I'm from Virginia. No? We're family.
特克·斯裏特爾總說 弗吉尼亞是得克薩斯的母親
You know, Tex Ritter always said Virginia was the mother of Texas.
我們一直不知道父親是誰 總懷疑是路易斯安那
Well, we never knew who the father was. We always suspected it was Louisiana.
我媽可喜歡這個笑話了
Oh! Huh? My mother loves that one.
是她想出來的 太有意思了
She was the one that came up with it. Oh, just so colorful.
你真有趣 你家可真漂亮
You're fun. This is a beautiful home.
參議員 競選活動怎麼樣?
So, h-how is the campaign going, Senator?
說實話 政治更像是我的一項愛好
Truth be told, politics is more of a hobby to me.
服事基督才是我的全職工作
Serving Christ, that's my full-time job.
現在美國正有一場針對宗教的戰爭
You know, there's a war on religion in this country.
有人說要怪科學
And some say science is to blame.
是科學讓我們今天齊聚一堂
Well, science is what brought us to this table.
你從阿波羅1號的事上學到了
You learned a little lesson on the provocation of pride
關於驕傲的一課 科爾 不是嗎?
on Apollo 1, now, didn't you, Cole?
其實科學讓我離上帝更近了 先生
Science has actually brought me closer to God, sir.
上帝用了六天創造了我們所知的一切
Took the Lord six days to put forth everything that we know as creation.
第六天 他把這些交給我們管理
And on that sixth day he gave us dominion over it.
我個人認為這是一種責任
And, personally, I take that as a responsibility.
你聽起來很虔誠
You sound like a man who knows his way to church.
我覺得最能體現虔誠的方法
Well, I can't think of a greater act of faith
莫過於追逐星辰
than pursuing the stars.
「諸天述說上帝的榮耀 穹蒼傳揚他的作為」
"The heavens declare the glory of God. And the firmament shows us his handiwork."
這是喬琳娜最喜歡的詩篇句子之一
That's one of Jolene's favorite Psalms.
是這樣 等我們的人從太空歸來
You see, our men, when they come back from space,
他們對上帝的信仰會更多 不會減少
they believe more in God, not less.
但我們登月時
But when we land on the moon,
多虧了這位瓊斯小姐 全球都能看到
and thanks to Miss Jones here, the world watches us do it.
我希望世界各地的人都能感受到 那種聖神的存在
And it's my hope that people everywhere feel the presence of that divine.
好吧
Well...
你的話確實得讓我好好想想 小伙子
you've, uh, certainly given me a lot to think about, son.
你這推銷還真有說服力啊
You really sold the hell out of that.
我沒在推銷
I wasn't selling.
鄭重聲明 做真實的自己也能贏得人心
For the record, you can win people over just by being who you are.
我們現在不趕時間了 所以不必飛回去
You know, we're not in a rush, so we don't really have to fly home.
那可不算飛
Ooh. That wasn't flying.
拜託 睜開眼睛
Come on. Open your eyes.
相信我嗎?
You trust me?
坐穩了
Hold tight.
現在才是最好玩的 滑下來就行
Now, this is the fun part. Just slide off.
完美
Perfect.
我過去對國家航空航天局的計劃 有過諸多意見不一致的地方
I've had my disagreements with the NASA program in the past.
但經過深思熟慮和反覆祈禱後
But after a great deal of thought, and prayer,
我決定投贊成票
I've decided to vote yes.
好樣的
Come on.
我有樣東西 你一定得看看
I have something that you need to see.
什麼... 跟我來
What... Follow me.
我之前不知道結果會如何
Whoo! I didn't know which way it was gonna go,
因為你根本看不透政客
'cause you can't tell with these guys.
我之前向來不喜歡這傢伙
I never liked that guy before, but...
但我現在喜歡他了
I like him now.
太好了
All right!
這裏好黑啊 你... 快到了
It's so dark in here. You... Almost there.
我有點害怕 好了 就在這裏
I'm a little scared. Yeah, it's right around here.
(對你的感謝有如登月往返)
我們想對你表達謝意
We wanted to show you our appreciation.
天啊 這也太隆重了 謝謝
Oh, my gosh. This is too much. Thank you.
不敢相信 都是沃爾特的功勞
I can't believe it. It was all Walter.
沃爾特? 我知道這都是你操辦的 對吧?
Oh, Walter? I know that you did all of this, didn't you?
出了點力而已 是 我知道是你
A little. That's all. Yeah, I know you did.
大家都幫忙了 還不錯吧?
They all helped. Not too bad, huh?
趁我還沒忘 給
Before I forget. Here.
這上面列出了 登月後你邁出第一步時可以說的話
It's a list of things for you to say when you take your first step.
我... 知道所有人都在問你 就是想給你些點子
I... I know everybody's asking you. I thought I'd give you some options.
我本來想說
Well, I was just gonna say,
「看這些酷酷的石頭」之類的話
"Look at all those cool rocks," or something.
我能搞定的 凱莉 好
I got this one, Kelly. Okay.
不過謝謝你
And thank you, though.
真心的 謝謝... 你所做的一切
And I mean it. For, uh... For everything.
我覺得沒有人比科爾·戴維斯 更在乎這個計劃
You know, I don't think anyone cares about this program more than Cole Davis.
很高興看見他有其他在乎的東西了
It's nice to see he's found something else to care about.
我知道我不是宇航員 但我能請你跳一支舞嗎?
I know I'm no, uh, astronaut, but can I steal you for a dance?
可以 可以? 來
Yes. Yes. Yeah? Come on.
你在數著日子 等待回到曼哈頓的那一天嗎?
So, you just counting down the days until you, uh, can get back to Manhattan?
並沒有
Not really.
很好
Good.
往上... 很好 好了 把燈搬過來
Up, up, up. Perfect. Right, now, move the light in.
好 繼續 別害羞
All right, keep going. Don't be shy.
繼續...
Keep going. Keep going. Keep going. Keep going. Keep going.
充分利用 很好
Milk it. Good. Mm-hmm.
女士們 覺得如何?
Ladies, what do we think?
蘭斯 太驚人了 很棒
Lance, it's incredible. It's great.
我覺得還需要再來點塵土和更好的演員
I think it needs a little more dust and better actors,
但我的要求被拒了
but I lost that battle.
我也就不糾結了
I will let it go.
停 好
And, stop. Okay.
我們有太陽了
We've got our sun.
我總是配合你編造的那些謊言
I always went along with every web you spun
要麼是因為它們很有趣 要麼我們是在騙壞人
because it was fun or, like, we were pulling one over on the bad guys,
但這次的感覺...
but this feels...
我知道
I know.
就快完工了
We're almost done.
這是我送你的
This is from me.
發射日禮物
It is for launch day.
答應我 到時候再拆
Promise you will wait until then.
我答應 好
I promise. Okay.
記住 你們不是怪獸
Remember, you're not monsters.
會跳那麼高嗎?
Are they gonna be that high?
我只需要讓他們的跳躍距離
Uh, I just need to give them any length
看起來像在月球上即可 但謝謝你的意見
that looks like they're on the moon. But thank you for the note.
巴茲 動作幅度小一點
Buzz, take it down some.
阿姆斯特朗 不要看我尋求肯定
And, Armstrong, stop looking at me for approval.
專心演好身處月球 把我當空氣 他排練得很開心...
Just be on the moon. I'm not here. He's having fun. He's having fun.
他總是和我四目相交 別暗送秋波了 專心演身處月球
He keeps locking eyes with me. Stop flirting and be on the moon.
昨天的科幻小說成為了今天的現實
Yesterday's science fiction is today's fact.
方法雖然不同
The methods are different,
但重要的是明天一早
but the important thing is that tomorrow morning,
人類將飛向月球
man will lift off toward the moon.
晚上好 我是沃爾特·克朗凱特
Good evening. I'm Walter Cronkite.
在人類首次登月之旅的前夕
And on this eve of man's first flight toward a landing on the moon,
所有的準備工作都很順利
all preparations go smoothly.
天氣預報狀況良好
The weather prediction,
還有宇航員們的幫助 尼爾 阿姆...
along with the health of astronauts, Neil Arm...
怎麼了?
Yes?
你很會傷人心啊
Well, you know how to hurt a fella.
禮貌性的電話都不打一個?
No courtesy call?
我沒有你的電話號碼
Well, I don't have your number.
你逃跑了
You ran.
這是你最擅長的事
That's what you do best.
你這個備用版本的登月是個錯誤 我原本就不該參與
Your alternate version is wrong. I never should've been a part of it.
我不幹了
I quit.
坐
Sit.
今天你要扮演誰呢?
So, who are we gonna be today?
我來看看
Let's see.
(目的地 希思羅機場)
海倫·帕克
Ooh, Helen Parker.
我打賭 你的英國口音一定很純正
I bet you do a killer British accent.
你想一走了之 去當海倫? 請便
You wanna take off and be Helen? Go ahead.
海倫不必提心吊膽地生活
Helen doesn't have to look over her shoulder.
沒有人會來找你的
No one is coming for you.
除非呢?
Unless?
除非你向任何人透露 阿爾忒彌斯計劃真實存在
Unless you ever tell anyone that Project Artemis was real,
登月是虛假拍攝的
and the moon landing was fake.
說到這個 計劃有變
Oh, on that score, change of plans.
我們會播出備用版本的登月
we're going to air the alternate version.
無論如何都播
No matter what.
你們從來沒打算播出真實的登月
Oh, you were never gonna broadcast the real thing.
這不光是登月競賽
This isn't just a race for the moon.
而是哪一種意識形態說了算的競賽
It is a race for which ideology gets to run things.
我讓一個手下改裝了登月艙攝像機 讓它只傳回聲音
I got one of my men to rig the LEM camera so that it just beams back audio.
我們會把他們的聲音同步到你的假舞台上
We're gonna sync with their sound and, uh, use your fake stage broadcast,
從頭到尾播出
start to finish.
讓我第一個代表美國感謝你
Let me be the first to thank you on behalf of America.
好了 別難過 人人都能得到想要的結果
Come on, don't feel bad. Everybody gets what they want.
你可以展開新生活 不必再逃避過往
You get a new life with no past to run from.
全世界也不必在共產主義的月光下入眠
And the world doesn't have to sleep under a communist moon.
好了 巴拿馬在召喚
Okay. Panama beckons.
你最好快點 要趕不上飛機了 海倫
You better hurry. You're going to... miss your flight, Helen.
這是為阿波羅號太空飛船上宇航員
This is a typical meal served to astronauts
提供的典型餐點
aboard Apollo space flights.
燕麥片 吐司
Oatmeal, toast,
和一個特製的零重力飲品袋 裝的是能量早餐飲品「果珍」
and a special zero-gravity pouch. Tang, the energy breakfast drink.
其維生素C含量超過橙汁
And more vitamin C than orange juice.
能量果珍 太空人和地球家庭的選擇
Energy Tang, for spacemen and Earth families.
哥倫比亞廣播公司呈獻 《月球上的人》
CBS News presents Man On the Moon.
講述阿波羅11號的史詩之旅
The epic journey of Apollo 11
就在這歷史性事件的前夕
on the eve of that historic event.
本節目由西部電氣贊助
Sponsored by Western Electric,
西部電氣 貝爾系統的製造和供應單位
manufacturing and supply unit of the Bell System.
本節目由國際紙業贊助 好主意在這裏繼續...
And by the International Paper Company, where good ideas roll on...
(阿波羅計劃中的人們)
(假日酒店 祝阿波羅11號馬到成功)
(私人活動 宇航員妻子的早午餐會)
你怎麼來了?
What are you doing here?
我得給你看一樣東西
I need to show you something.
這本來是個應急計劃
It was supposed to be a contingency plan.
他是這樣說服我的 就是個保險措施
That's how he sold it. It was an insurance policy.
以防我們失敗
In case we failed.
知道了也好
It's good to know...
你從來沒相信過我們
that you never believed in us.
我知道你很難過
I know you're upset.
我理解 你理解什麼?
I understand... Oh, what do you understand?
請告訴我你理解什麼
Please tell me what you understand.
因為你對真相一點都不理解
'Cause you don't understand shit about truth.
如果你偽造這次任務...
If you fake this mission... If you fake this mission,
那我們之前做出的每一次犧牲全都白費了
every single thing that we have sacrificed will have been for nothing.
我知道我搞砸了 我知道
I know I messed up. I know that.
但你心裏清楚 如果沒有我 你們根本走不到今天
But you know you couldn't have made it to this day without me.
我昨晚大可一走了之 但我沒有
I could've walked away last night, but I didn't.
我回來是為了彌補這個錯誤
I came back to fix this.
彌補什麼?
Fix what?
莫切斷了登月艙的畫面 如果我們不一起修好它
Moe cut the LEM camera, and if we don't fix this together
那全世界看到的將會是這個版本
then this is gonna be the version that the world sees.
這不是應急計劃
It's not a contingency.
天啊 你總能讓我別無選擇
God, you're so good at leaving me no options.
好吧 我們去修好它
Fine, let's fix it.
但等這事結束 我再也不想看到你
But when this is over, I never wanna see your face again.
為理查德·尼克松做事就是這種下場
This is what happens when you work for Richard Nixon.
我看了你的素描本 露比
I got your book, Ruby.
你提早拆開了
You opened it early.
拆得正是時候
It came at just the right time.
適合發射的大氣層
Proper atmosphere for launch
是氧氣和氮氣的混合物
which is a combination of oxygen and nitrogen.
60%的氧氣和40%氮氣的大氣層
Sixty percent oxygen and 40% nitrogen atmosphere.
當然 宇航員們呼吸的是
Of course, the astronauts themselves are breathing pure oxygen
太空服提供的純氧
through their space suits.
很快將進行另一次關鍵測試
Coming up shortly will be another key test
屆時發射組...
in which both the, uh, launch crew for the...
發射載具組員和飛船乘組
the launch vehicle crew and the spacecraft team,
會和指揮官尼爾·阿姆斯特朗一起
uh, combine together with the commander, Neil Armstrong,
徹查緊急情況檢測系統
to make a thorough check of the Emergency Detection System.
這就是該系統...
This is the system...
我們正在卡納維拉爾角直播 這創造歷史的一天天氣晴好
We're live from the Cape, where it's a beautiful day to make history.
我們將在這裏為大家直播發射的部分
We'll be handling the launch portion of the broadcast from here,
我們在休斯敦的同行
and our counterparts in Houston
將報道任務控制中心引導的
will be covering Apollo 11's historic flight,
阿波羅11號歷史性的航程
guided by Mission Control.
各位
Guys!
壞了
It's busted.
攝像機的視頻前置放大器
The camera's video preamplifier.
壞掉了 好吧 你能修好嗎?
It's destroyed. Okay, can you fix that?
我也許能從電視上拆一個改裝 但...
I could maybe repurpose a part from a TV, but...
好啊 這裏有很多電視
Well, that's fine. There's plenty of TVs around here.
航天局的電視都太老舊了
NASA's TVs... They are all too old.
我要一台全新的晶體管彩色電視
I mean a brand-new solid-state color TV.
你多快能弄到一台?
Well, how fast can you get one?
你送我去電器商店最快要多久?
How fast can you get me to an electronics store?
我? 現在佛羅里達交通空前擁堵
Me? In the worst traffic in Florida history.
走不開 得給大家做準備
I can't. I have to prep the guys.
把鑰匙給我
Give me the keys.
好吧 我來拖延
Fine, I'll stall.
快點 去吧...
Hurry. Go, go, go, go, go, go, go.
所有酒店全部爆滿
Hotels are at capacity.
肯尼迪航天中心人滿為患
Kennedy Space Center is so crowded,
我們聽說進出幾乎不可能
we're hearing it's nearly impossible to get in or out.
凱莉 開慢點
Kelly, slow down.
後面兩位還好嗎?
Are you guys good back there?
很好 不好
Yes. No.
請別這樣...
Please, please stop. Please stop.
到了 就是這家店
There it is. There's the store.
不 關門了
No! They're closed.
關門了 什麼?
They're closed. Oh, what?
不... 沒關門
No, no. No, they are not.
凱莉
Kelly. Whoa, whoa, whoa. Whoa!
你們還等什麼呢? 快去
What are you waiting for? Go!
是... 好
Oh. Yeah, yeah. Okay.
好
Okay.
Okay, um...
對 這一台 很好 對 好
Yes, this one. This is great. Yeah, okay.
我很想幫忙 只是我不夠高 來吧 唐 好
I would help. I'm just not tall enough. Come on, Don. All right.
好 慢點 好的 各位 快點
All right. Slowly, all right. Guys, come on.
天啊 我可不能蹲監獄
Oh, my God. I can't go to jail.
交給我
Let me handle this.
(警察)
她真厲害
She's good.
是啊
Yeah.
一路順風 兄弟們
Have a good ride, boys.
大約五分鐘後
In a matter of, uh, five minutes or so
我們將看到飛船指揮官尼爾·阿姆斯特朗
we'll be ready for the spacecraft commander, Neil Armstrong,
跨過位於98米高空的舷門門檻
to come across the sill at the 320-foot level.
搭乘穿梭麵包車... 快啊
The trip in the transfer van... Come on!
大約要15分鐘才能抵達發射平台
Could take some 15 minutes or so to reach the pad.
屆時 宇航員將搭乘 兩部電梯中先來的那部
At which time the astronauts will board, uh, the first of two elevators
前往發射平台所在的98米高空
for the trip to the 320-foot level at the launchpad,
然後進入飛船
uh, where they will then proceed to ingress the spacecraft.
站住 已經準備就緒了 小伙子
Whoa. We are locked and loaded, kid.
不... 飛行部要把這個放進飛船
No, no. Flight Deck wants this on the ship.
這裏飛行部 放他過去 好
This is Flight Deck. Let him through. Got it.
去吧
Go.
好 我們必須啟動發射前的程序了 否則會錯過窗口期
Okay, we need to initiate prelaunch, or we lose the window.
給他一分鐘就好
Just give him one minute.
... 98米的高空
320-foot level,
三位宇航員都已登上飛船
all three astronauts now aboard the spacecraft.
幾分鐘前 宇航員巴茲·奧爾德林 進來坐在了中間的位置
A few minutes ago, Astronaut Buzz Aldrin, uh, came in and took the center seat...
我聽說船艙已經封閉 倒計時開始了
I'm hearing the cabin's now being sealed. Countdown has begun.
這是他們發射時的姿態
These are the positions they will fly at liftoff.
指揮官 這裏是飛船測試員 聽得清楚嗎?
CDR, STC, how do you read?
飛船測試員 聽得很清楚
STC, loud and clear.
早上好 尼爾 發射架已撤開
Good morning, Neil. Gantry is cleared.
歡迎登船
Welcome aboard.
阿波羅11號準備發射 倒計時十分鐘
Apollo 11 is a go for launch in T-minus ten minutes.
好
Okay.
他回來了
He's here.
接上了
It's connected.
至少我認為接上了
At least I think I connected it.
斯圖 什麼意思?
Stu, what the hell does that mean?
我只有幾秒鐘時間 沒來得及進行壓力測試 我...
I only had a few seconds. I didn't have time to stress test it. I...
好 坐下吧
Okay. Sit down.
好 都聽著
All right, listen up!
無論今天這裏發生什麼
Whatever happens here today,
我都會支持你們做出的每一個決定
I will stand by every decision that you make.
近十年來 超過四十萬人參與了這項計劃
Over 400,000 people have worked on this program for nearly ten years.
就為了實現一個人對全世界的承諾
All to keep one man's promise to the world.
讓我們堅守這個承諾吧
So, let's keep it.
好了 告訴我發射是否就緒吧
All right. Give me, "Go/No go" for launch.
收到 所有崗位 準備進行最後的就緒核查
Ah, roger. All stations, stand by for final "Go/No go."
機械姿態電控 就緒
MACE. Go.
環境控制系統 就緒
ECS. Go.
電力系統 就緒
EPS. Go.
序列控制器 就緒
Sequencer. Go.
導航系統 就緒
GNS. Go.
航天器控制系統 這裏最精彩了
SCS. This is the best part.
他們依次問下去 每一個...
They go down the line and every single...
每一個技術員都必須說 發射「就緒」或「未就緒」
every single technician has to say, "Go," or, "No go," for launch.
任何一人都能阻止發射
Any one of them can stop it.
CFAT CSE 現在能回答「就緒」了嗎?
CFAT. CSE, can you give me a "go" now?
CSE就緒
CSE is go.
好 鷹號就緒
Okay. Uh, Eagle is go.
CBTS 這裏是CSA9號
CBTS, this is CSA 9.
倒計時20秒
Twenty seconds and counting.
倒計時15秒 制導系統已切換為自主模式
T-minus 15 seconds. Guidance is internal.
十二 十一 十 九...
Twelve, eleven, ten, nine...
點火程序啟動
Ignition sequence starts.
五 四 三 二 一
Five, four, three, two, one.
所有引擎啟動
All engines running.
發射 火箭升空
Liftoff. We have liftoff.
發射塔已分離
Tower clear.
休斯敦 交給你了
Houston, she's all yours.
莫·伯克斯來了 要找你們倆
Moe Berkus is here. For both of you.
阿波羅11號已經升空
Apollo 11 is on the way.
四十萬公里之外
250,000 miles away,
月球在等待人類的首次到來
where the moon is waiting for man's first arrival.
整個航程要用三天時間
Flight to take, uh, three days.
飛船要抵達...
And, uh, the, uh, spacecraft to reach there...
凱莉全都告訴我了
Kelly told me everything.
好極了
Bravissimo.
省省吧 這是創造歷史
Shove it. That was history.
嗨 海倫 抱歉 是凱莉
Hi, Helen. Uh, sorry, Kelly.
我聽說你回來了 所以我也回來了
I heard you came back, so I came back too.
我... 去月球片場看了一眼
I... I took a little peeky-poo at the moon set,
真是完美
and it is perfection.
幹得好
Great job.
如果你認為我會讓你播出 這次任務的造假版本
If you think that I'm gonna let you broadcast some fake version of this,
那我現在就去找媒體
I'll go to the press right now.
科爾
Cole.
科爾...
Cole. Cole.
你... 去找媒體吧 帶他們看看月球片場
You, uh... You go to the press. Bring 'em by the moon set,
但你要知道 今後再也不會有人相信國家航空航天局了
but just know that no one will ever trust the legitimacy of NASA again.
這是國家安全問題
This is a matter of national security.
本次直播必須在可控的情況下進行
This broadcast must take place in a controlled setting.
你應該最明白了
You of all people must understand that.
任務的重點已經不再是登月了
The mission isn't about landing on the moon anymore.
而是全世界在電視上觀看美國戰勝蘇聯
It is about the world watching America beat Russia on TV.
我得趕飛機
I got a flight to catch.
我會及時趕回來看登月直播的
I'll be back in time for the lunar broadcast.
我想在這裏看
I thought I'd watch it here.
凱莉 和你一起在月球片場看
With you, Kelly. On the moon.
嘿 我們正在創造歷史
Hey. We're making history.
你說我的那些話全都沒錯
Everything you said about me is true.
我是個騙子 一直都是
I'm a con artist, and I always have been.
我的真名甚至不是凱莉
My real name is not even Kelly.
那些我跟你講的故事
All those stories that I told you
說我和我媽挨家挨戶推銷
about my mom and I selling products door-to-door,
那是真事
those were true.
但都是騙局
They were all scams.
我們開始只是小打小鬧 之後越做越大
And we started out small, and then they got bigger.
大到涉及地產和保險什麼的
Like real estate and insurance.
然後...
And...
我16歲那年 在北達科他州 有個人掏槍了
when I was 16, a guy in North Dakota pulled a gun
我媽比他更快掏出槍 把他打死了
and my mom pulled hers out first and she killed him.
她叫我逃跑 我照做了
And she told me to run and I did.
她進了監獄 我再也沒見過她
And she went to prison and I never saw her again.
我偽造文件 用假名來找工作
And I forged documents and used fake names to get jobs.
我去紐約後發現了廣告業
And when I went to New York, I found advertising.
就像我媽教我的騙局 但卻合法
And that was like the scams that my mom taught me, but it was legal.
我騙了很多人
And I lied to so many people.
最糟糕的謊言是我對自己說的那些
The worst lies were the ones I told myself.
說所有人都在騙人 這只是一場大型遊戲而已
That everybody does it. You know. It's just a big game.
但後來我來了這裏
But then I came down here...
認識了你
I met you.
我瞭解到參與到真實事件中是什麼感受
I learned what it was like to be a part of something real.
莫提出的條件是抹去我的黑歷史
Moe offered me a way to erase my past.
我原以為那就是我想要的 但...
I thought that's what I wanted, but...
我不想再逃亡了
I don't wanna run anymore.
莫是個值得尊敬的對手 但他遇到旗鼓相當的人了
Moe is a worthy opponent, but he has met his match.
我保證這是我最後一次 用欺騙的手段來獲取我想要的東西
I promise this is the last time I will trick anyone into getting what I want.
我保證
I promise.
你覺得不撒謊也能做到嗎?
Do you think you can do it without lying?
絕對不行 好吧 我想也是
Absolutely not. Yeah, I didn't think so.
那你有什麼計劃?
So, what's the plan?
我們為什麼在這裏碰頭?
Why are we meeting out here?
因為莫監聽一切對話 這人就像個魔術師 無處不在
Because Moe bugs everything. The guy's like Houdini. He's everywhere.
好 莫不知道我們修好了登月艙攝像機
Okay, so, Moe doesn't know that we fixed the LEM camera.
我們就此來制定計劃
We build a plan around that.
我們只需讓他相信我們在直播假登月
All we have to do is convince him that we are broadcasting the fake moon landing,
而實際上我們在播真的
when in reality we're broadcasting the real one.
我們有沒有辦法給設備動手腳
Is there a way that we could rig the equipment
來播出真實的登月艙視頻?
so that it actually sends out the real LEM video feed?
拜託 兩位
Come on, boys.
你們連登月都搞定了 給我個假設理論啊
You figured out how to land on the moon. Give me a hypothetical.
好 假設的話 我們可以重新接線
Okay, um, hypothetically, we could rewire it.
讓設備只接收任務控制中心的播出信號
So that it only picks up the broadcast signal from Mission Control.
好 然後和我們的信號同步 對
Sure, then sync it with our feed. Hmm. Right.
嘿 各位
Hey, fellas.
莫·伯克斯派這兩位來測試播出信號
Moe Berkus sent these guys to test the broadcast feed.
莫... 伯克斯 對 莫·伯克斯...
Moe... Moe Berk... Yes. Moe Berk... Moe Berkus.
你們誰都沒接到電話?
Telling me none of you got the phone call?
好極了 攝像機在哪?
Great. All right, where's the camera?
你還好嗎?
Are you okay? Mmm.
請你們快點好嗎?
Can you guys hurry up, please?
唐 你把煙掐了吧
Don, maybe just take the cigarette out.
抱歉... 我之前從沒吸過煙
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I've just never smoked a cigarette before.
我不喜歡
I don't like it.
11號 這裏是休斯敦
Uh, 11, this is Houston.
環月軌道進入就緒 完畢
Uh, you are go for LOI. Over.
確認 向月球前進
Confirmed. On track for the moon.
阿波羅11號 這裏是休斯敦
Apollo 11, this is Houston.
你的全部系統正常 要轉到月球後面了
All your systems are looking good. Going around the corner.
我們另一邊見 完畢
We'll see you on the other side. Over.
我們失去了信號
And we've had loss of signal
因為阿波羅11號飛到了月球後面
as Apollo 11 goes behind the moon.
現在是東部夏令時下午3點半
It's now 3:30 Eastern Daylight Time.
3點46分時 我們應該能夠收到 登月艙的第一個信號
At 3:46 we should be getting the first signal from the Lunar Module.
估計觀眾有上億人
The estimated audience: hundreds of millions.
可能有四億人
Perhaps 400 million persons or so are watching
正在觀看這一重大事件的直播...
this broadcast today of, uh, the greatest event...
兄弟們
Boys.
好 開始吧
All right. Let's go.
再往下一點 很好 各位
A little bit more. Well done, guys.
夥計們 你們聽到我說話 就當成是上帝的旨意
Boys, when you hear my voice, you hear God.
這是個假月球
Now, this is a fake moon,
但對於全世界 這是真的 好戲上演了
but to the world, it's real. It's showtime, folks.
必須... 記住我說到哪了
It needs to... Remember where I left off.
政府感謝你們即將付出的努力
Your government thanks you for the work you're about to do.
別搞砸了
Now, don't fuck it up.
這破爛飲料為什麼放這裏?
What is this nasty shit doing here?
天啊 不好意思
God. Excuse me.
這是本片場指定的汽水 這是我的椅子
This is a Tab set, and that is my chair.
凱莉 處理一下 蘭斯 非常感謝
Kelly, let's deal with this. Lance, thank you so much.
這些屏幕是我們的信號
So, these screens... This is our feed.
好 然後...
Yeah. Okay. And then...
電視是直播畫面 好
And the TV's a live broadcast. Okay.
(阿波羅11號 月球直播)
對
Right.
約瑟夫 我要坐下
Joseph, I'm sitting.
天啊 你認真的?
Oh, my God. Are you real?
我是導演 蘭斯·瓦斯珀丁
I am the director, Lance Vespertine.
別礙事好嗎?
Stay out of my way, will you?
好 我想說很高興認識你 但到目前為止我不高興
All right, I'd say it was nice to meet you, but so far, it is not.
鴿子已經進籠
The pigeon's in the coop.
收到
Copy that.
好 應該能收到了 休斯敦
Okay, you should have him now, Houston.
鷹號 我們有你的信號了 看起來不錯 完畢
Eagle, we've got you now. It's looking good. Over.
我們從前窗就可以看到地球
We've got the Earth right out of our front window.
飛行指揮 我們準備著陸
Flight, we are go for landing.
收到 明白 準備著陸 910米
Roger. Understand. Go for landing. 3,000 feet.
鷹號 狀態很好 可以開始著陸
Eagle, looking great. You're go.
位置檢查顯示 水平飛行距離有些過長
Position checks downrange show us to be a little long.
430米 狀態依然很好
1,400 feet. Still looking very good.
P30 6加2.5
P30. Six plus two-five.
看起來大約250米
Looks like about 820.
降低引擎的功率
Throttle down.
飛行指揮 這裏是鷹號
Flight, this is Eagle.
寧靜海裏的石頭比預期中多
Sea of Tranquility is rockier than expected.
我們不得不再飛300米
We're gonna have to extend another thousand feet.
嘿 兄弟們
Hey, boys.
那樣的話情況如何?
Where does that put us?
他們會剩下15秒的燃料 最好終止任務
It'll give 'em 15 seconds of fuel left. They're gonna wanna abort.
尼爾能做到 只要放手讓他飛即可
Neil can do this, they just gotta let him.
待命 鷹號
Stand by, Eagle.
(燃料百分比)
我們正在計算延長飛行的耗油量
We are calculating what that will do to our fuel reserves.
電氣 環境和耗材主管計算 是15秒以內 準備終止任務
EECOM puts that within 15 seconds. Prepare for abort.
飛行指揮
Flight...
我們曾在這個範圍內 進行過成功測試 讓他們著陸吧
we have run successful tests within that range. Let 'em land.
30秒...
Thirty. Thirty seconds.
這是騙人 你撒謊了
That's a lie. You lied.
我新學了幾招 坐下
I've learned some new tricks. Sit down.
好 接下來只報告燃料數字
Okay, the only callouts from now on will be fuel.
加油啊
Come on.
鷹號 看起來不錯 可以著陸
Eagle, looking great. You're go.
430米 狀態依然很好
1,400 feet. Still looking very good.
107米 降速4
350 feet, down at four.
30秒...
Thirty. Thirty seconds.
降速2.5 前進
Down two and a half. Forward.
前進 好 收到
Forward. Good. Roger that.
前進速度11 正穩步下降
Eleven forward. Coming down nicely.
61米 降速4.5
200 feet, four and a half down.
降速5.5... 前進速度9
Five and a half down. Five and a half down, nine forward.
很好
That's good.
(月表接觸)
接觸燈亮了
Contact light.
關閉引擎
Engine stop.
飛行指揮
Flight.
這裏是寧靜海基地
Tranquility Base here.
鷹號已著陸
The Eagle has landed.
收到 寧靜海基地 地面收到
Roger, Tranquility, we copy on the ground.
有一群人臉都快憋青了
You got a bunch of guys about to turn blue.
我們又能呼吸了 多謝
We're breathing again. Thanks a lot.
呼 老天
Whew. Boy.
我們要忙一會兒了
We're going to be busy for a minute.
好了... 可以了
All right, all right, all right. Come on.
集中注意力 還沒完呢
Let's focus. We're only halfway there.
好 接下來交給我們 謝謝各位
Yeah, we've got it from here. Thank you, guys.
大家各就各位... 打起精神
Places. Places, everyone. Look sharp.
打起精神來
Let's look sharp!
愛德華... 走下舞台 真要命
Edvard, Edvard, off the stage. You're killing me.
愛德華 完事了 停 你完工了 別再調整了
Edvard, we are done. Uh-uh. You're done. No more tweaking.
你是復讀機嗎? 我不是復讀機
What are you, the repeater? No, I'm not the repeater.
這是你來之前我們創立的系統
This is the system we created before you got here.
已取下攝像機
Camera is coming down.
(直播中)
三 二 一 開拍
Three, two, one, and action.
電視上有畫面了
And we're getting a picture on the TV.
畫面還不錯吧?
You got a good picture, huh?
對比度很強烈
Uh, there's a great deal of contrast in it.
收到 電視電路斷路器已接通
Roger, TV circuit breaker's in,
聽得很清楚
and read you loud and clear.
收到
Roger.
好 請確認一下
Okay. Will you verify the position, uh,
攝像機鏡頭的位置和光圈尺寸
the, uh, opening I ought to have on the camera?
稍等
Stand by.
阿姆斯特朗 準備下飛船
Armstrong, prepare to disembark.
遮光面罩
Your visor.
我要打開艙門出去了
I am opening the door for egress.
好 尼爾 我們看到你正走下舷梯
Okay, Neil, we can see you coming down the ladder now.
好 左腳
Okay, left.
右腳
And right.
左腳 右腳
Left and right.
好 左腳下來...
Now, left foot off. Left foot off.
慢點... 下來
Easy. Easy. Step down.
落地
And land.
你怎麼提前知道他要做什麼?
How do you know what, uh, he's gonna do ahead of time?
國家航空航天局全都排練過 凱莉借鑒了一下
NASA rehearsed all of this, and Kelly appropriated it.
就是偷嘛
Oh, stole it.
我就知道我找對人了
I knew I hired the right people.
好 來吧
Okay, here we go.
(真實信號 播出信號)
天衣無縫 真難以置信
It's seamless. It's incredible.
我來到舷梯底部了
I'm at the foot of the ladder.
登月艙的支腳僅僅壓進月球表面2到5厘米
The LEM footpads are only depressed in the surface about one or two inches,
不過靠近了看 月表的塵土似乎非常細膩
although the surface appears to be very, very fine-grained as you get close to it.
幾乎就像粉末 下面的塵埃非常細
It's almost like a powder. Down there, it's very fine.
我要走下登月艙了
I'm gonna step off the LEM now.
這是個人的一小步
That's one small step for man...
卻是人類的一大步
one giant leap for mankind.
這麼精彩的話 我們可能得花好幾年才想得出
We could have spent years coming up with something that good.
是的
Yeah.
這是劇本裏的嗎?
Was that, uh, in the script?
不是
No.
這句台詞不錯
That's a good line.
一級一級舷梯跳下來是很簡單的
It's a very simple matter to hop down from one step to the next.
尼爾要展示牌匾了
Neil is now unveiling the plaque.
「地球的人類
"Here man, from the planet Earth,
於公元1969年7月首次踏上月球
first set foot upon the moon, July 1969 AD.
我們為全人類的和平而來」
We came in peace for all mankind."
準備好上鏡了嗎?
You ready for the camera?
尼爾 這裏是休斯敦 視野正常
Uh, Neil, this is Houston. The field of view is okay.
我們希望你把攝像機對準右邊一點 完畢
We'd like you to aim it a little bit more to the right. Over.
好
Okay.
太往右了
Too much to the right.
能往左4 5度嗎?
Can you bring it back left about, uh, four or five degrees?
好 看起來不錯 尼爾
Okay. That looks good, Neil.
哥倫比亞號... 這裏是休斯敦 接收信號 完畢
Columbia, Columbia, this is Houston, AOS. Over.
尼爾阿姆斯特朗目前已經在月球表面
Neil Armstrong has been on the lunar surface now
停留近45分鐘了
almost 45 minutes.
寧靜海基地 這裏是休斯敦
Uh, Tranquility Base, this is Houston.
請兩位一起走進鏡頭一下好嗎?
Could we get both of you on the camera for a minute, please?
美國總統想跟你們說幾句 完畢
The President of the United States would like to say a few words to you. Over.
這是我們的榮幸
That would be an honor.
好 總統先生 請講吧
All right, go ahead, Mr. President.
這裏是休斯敦 完畢
This is Houston. Out.
你們好 尼爾和巴茲
Hello, Neil and Buzz.
我正在白宮的橢圓辦公室 用電話跟你們通話
I am talking to you by telephone from the Oval Room at the White House...
這地方到處都是特勤局的人
They have Secret Service all over this place.
這絕對是有史以來最重要的一次通話
And this certainly has to be the most historic telephone call ever made.
你們跟我們通話的同時...
And as you talk to us...
我覺得你跟他真的很像
He actually reminds me a lot of you.
別這麼說 真的 連玩笑都別開
Do not say that. No, don't even joke about that.
總統發表無聊講話時我們要待命 別動
We're still holding while the president drones on. Don't move.
阿姆斯特朗 我主要盯著你
Armstrong, I'm watching you the most.
在這全人類史上無比珍貴的時刻...
For one priceless moment in the whole history of man...
肯尼迪航天中心 我們直接通話吧
Kennedy, let's go direct.
科爾 你收到畫面了嗎?
Cole, are you receiving picture?
這邊的視頻信號燈沒亮
The video feed light isn't on up here.
尼爾 什麼意思? 壞掉了?
Uh, what do you mean, Neil? It's not working?
那得你來告訴我 你能看到畫面嗎?
You tell me. Do you see picture?
我們的攝像機發出了電力過載警報
We're getting a power surge warning on the camera.
好像壞了 你還能看到我們嗎?
I think it crapped out. Can you still see us?
能 還能看見
Yeah, I can still see you.
稍等 尼爾
Um, one second, Neil.
尼爾說月球上的視頻信號燈沒有亮
Neil's saying the video feed light isn't on up there.
你確定那台攝像機能用?
Are you sure that camera's working?
我安裝了新零件 應該沒問題的 但...
I installed the new part. It should be working just fine but...
但什麼? 但我... 當時趕時間
But what? But I... I was in a rush.
見鬼
Shit.
怎麼了?
What's wrong?
我們不確定登月艙上的 攝像機是否運作正常
We're not sure that the camera on the LEM is working.
我覺得播出的畫面是你們的
I think that's your feed broadcasting.
電視上的畫面和片場一樣嗎?
Does the feed on your TV look like your set?
我... 看不出是不是我們
I... I can't tell if it's us.
測試一下 讓一個特工揮揮手什麼的
Test it. Have one of your agents give a little wave or something.
不行 所有人都在這裏
I can't. Everyone is here.
這是什麼鬼? 我不知道
What the hell is that? I don't know.
他差5厘米就進鏡頭了
He is two inches away from being on that screen.
是... 2厘米
It's... It's one inch.
這也是你那該死的劇本裏的情節?
Is that in your goddamn script?
約瑟夫 有新加的戲?
Joseph, were there new pages?
不僅代表美國
Representing not only the United States
也代表所有國家熱愛和平的人
but men of peace of all nations...
是小淘氣 天啊 貓咪...
Oh, Mischief! Oh, God. Kitty, kitty! Pss, kitty, kitty, kitty.
小淘氣...
Mischief! Mischief!
你去哪?
Where are you going?
小淘氣... 凱莉
Mischief. Mischief. K... Kelly.
過來 那隻貓?
Come here. The cat?
過來...
Come here. Come here. Come here.
你認識這隻貓?
Do you know this cat?
貓咪...
Kitty, kitty, kitty!
過來 小寶... 過來 你個小混蛋
Come here, you sweet... Come here, you little bitch.
貓咪...
Kitty, kitty, kitty.
給我過來 不
Come here, you! No!
凱莉 你那邊到底怎麼了?
Kelly, what the hell is going on over there?
凱莉?
Kelly? Kelly?
繞到後面去
Go round the back!
小淘氣...
Mischief! Mischief!
貓咪...
Kitty, kitty, kitty!
抓住它... 快...
Catch him! Catch him! Oh! Go, go.
我們走 快
Let's go! Come on.
來 沒事的
Come here. It's okay.
小淘氣 過來吧
Mischief. Just come here.
閉嘴...
Just shut up. Just shut up!
過來 貓咪... 過來 小寶寶 你認識我的
Come here, kitty, kitty, kitty. Come here, little baby. You know me.
不
No!
非常感謝
And thank you very much
我很期待 我們都很期待
and I look forward, all of us look forward,
星期四在大黃蜂號上見到你們
to seeing you on the Hornet on Thursday.
我也很期待 先生
I look forward to that very much, sir.
播出的是你的人 科爾
Those are your guys, Cole.
太好了 是我們的人
Yes! Those are our guys!
對 我知道你們都知道
Yes. I know you know that.
就是提醒一下大家我們今天在幹什麼
Just reminding everybody what we're doing here today.
那是我們的人
Those are our guys.
大家繼續忙吧
Carry on.
我看到的是什麼?
What am I looking at here?
月球
Oh, that's the moon.
尼爾 這裏是休斯敦
Neil, this is Houston.
你拿哈蘇雜誌...
Did you get the Hasselblad magazine...
真的是月球?
That's really the moon?
拿了 我們有大約...
Yes, I did. And we got about, uh...
老天 看起來好假 得有9公斤...
Jesus, it looks fake. I'd say 20 pounds of, uh...
精挑細選 但沒有記錄的樣品
carefully selected, if not documented samples.
休斯敦 收到 好樣的 完畢
Houston.
非官方時間 離開地面111小時37分32秒
Roger. Well done. Out. Unofficial time off the surface at 111:37:32.
我從沒想過自己能這麼近地看到月球
I never thought I would see the moon up close.
我也一樣 沃爾特
Me neither, Walter.
我沒搞定 天啊 抱歉
I didn't get it. Oh, my God. Sorry.
別和上次一樣 不 別衝著我們開
Not like last time. No. Don't point it at us.
在波蘭 我們說「na zdrowie」
In Polish, we call it "na zdrowie."
好 na zdrowie 好... 凱莉
All right. Na zdrowie. Okay, okay, okay. Kelly.
凱莉... 好點了
Kelly. Kelly. It's getting a little better.
什麼事? 老天 說吧 就說一次
Yes? What? Christ, just say it. Just say it once.
你是我認識的最棒的導演
You are the best director I know.
是的 好了 我知道此事要保密
I am. [inhales sharply] Now, I know we're not supposed to talk about this,
但是凱莉 能寫進我的簡歷就太好了 如果我... 感覺...
but, Kelly, this would be so great on my resume if I... Just feels...
任何人把此事透露出去
Anyone mentions this to anyone,
就會在一個無名島上陰暗的牢房裏
you will spend the rest of your life in a dark, dank prison cell
度過餘生
on a nameless island.
好了 為了配合香檳酒
Oh. Now, to wash down the bubbly,
我代表美國政府請大家喝蘇格蘭威士忌
on behalf of the US government, have a little, uh, scotch.
愛德華
Hmm. Edvard.
我來一杯
I'll take one of those.
我做了一檔價值十億美元的電視節目 但觀眾只有一個人
I had a billion-dollar TV show for an audience of one.
希望你看得開心
Hope you enjoyed it.
乾杯 這是一場完美的失敗
Cheers. It was a perfect failure.
對 乾杯... 乾杯
That's right. Cheers. Cheers. Cheers.
能聊幾句嗎?
Can I talk with you a moment?
沒有多少人違抗了我的命令
Not many people have gone against my orders
還能活命的
and lived to talk about it.
不過話說回來 也沒有多少人救過我
Then again, not many people have saved my ass.
要解釋月球上為什麼有隻貓 那可太難了
It would've been a real doozy to explain how the cat ended up on the moon.
你真是個美國英雄
You're a goddamn American hero.
幹得好
Great job.
好了 現在這裏到處都是媒體
Now, this place is crawling with press.
濺落之前 我們無法清理這裏
So, uh, we can't really clear anything out until after splashdown.
在這期間呢 把一切和拍攝有關的文件全部銷毀
In the meantime, shred any documents associated with the shoot.
你的名字會從史冊中抹去
Your name will be wiped from the history books.
過往將被重寫
The story, rewritten.
那我可以走了 是的
Then I'm free to go. You are.
不過呢 有個未來的項目 我需要你這樣的人幫忙
Although, I could use someone like you for an upcoming project.
不 謝了
No, thanks.
你隨意吧 我不理解 但沒問題
Suit yourself. Hard to get, but okay.
如果需要我 喊一聲就行 我可能會聽見
If you ever need me... just holler. I'm probably listening.
莫
Oh. Moe.
真有外星人嗎?
Are there really aliens out there?
外星人就生活在我們中間
They walk among us.
帶我飛向月球
Fly me to the moon
讓我們在群星中嬉戲
Let's play among the stars
讓我看看木星和火星上春天的樣子
Let me see what spring is like On Jupiter and Mars...
四十萬公里
A quarter of a million miles.
想想尼爾·阿姆斯特朗的話
Just think of it as, uh, Neil Armstrong said,
人類踏上月球時的第一句話
the first words as man stepped foot on the moon,
「這是個人的一小步 卻是人類的一大步」
"A small step for man, a giant leap for mankind."
這一天不會再有了
And a day that can never come again.
這一天和這一句話將永遠載入史冊
A day that shall forever live in history, as will those words,
會被學生們記住
which will be memorized by schoolboys...
阿姆斯特朗 你很有前途 不過不是演戲 天啊 絕對不是
Armstrong, you've got a future. Not in acting. My God, no.
凱莉 帕蒂... 是叫帕蒂吧?
Well, Kelly, Patty... Patty, right?
我叫露比 好
My name is Ruby. Uh-huh.
我們成功了 不 我們沒成功
We did it. No, we didn't.
這裏是近陸地單位
This is, uh, landward here.
游泳1號看到阿波羅號了
Uh, Swim One has Apollo visual.
如果它正在14.5公里外下降
Well, if it's coming down nine miles away,
那將會剛好落在能見度極限範圍內
uh, that's just going to be at the, uh, outer limit of, uh, visibility...
加油... 寶貝...
Come on. Come on, baby. Come on, baby.
他們從月球返回了
They're back from the moon.
宇航員阿姆斯特朗 奧爾德林和柯林斯
Astronauts Armstrong, Aldrin and Collins
降落在太平洋 夏威夷的西南方
landing in the Pacific Ocean, southwest of Hawaii.
我想你應該抽一支煙
I guess you deserve a cigarette.
朋友 是... 我...
Aw, buddy. Yeah, yeah. I, uh...
我不想在裏面失控
I didn't wanna lose it in there. You know?
我知道你不希望帶攝像機登月
You know, I know you didn't want the camera up there,
但是 天啊 看到那畫面...
but, man, seeing that was, uh...
足以改變人生
It was life-changing.
我們成功了 是的... 哥們
We did it. We did. We did, man.
嘿 現在1969年 對吧? 我們在這個十年內做到了
Hey, it's 1969, right? We got it in before the decade.
是啊 踩著時間線呢 是的 我們成功了
I know. Not a moment to spare. Oh. Yeah, we did.
瞧 那是誰 嘿
Look who it is. Hey.
去吧 走吧 好
Go. Get out of here. Yeah.
聽著 你也不晚 小子
Listen, uh, it's not too late for you either, kid.
謝謝你 亨利 好了
Thank you, Henry. All right.
嘿
Hey.
我們成功了
We did it.
嗨 孩子們
Hey, guys, huh?
把人送上了月球
Sent a man to the moon.
知道嗎...
You know...
我還不知道你的名字呢
I never did catch your name.
溫妮
Winnie.
溫妮 很高興認識你 溫妮
Winnie. Nice to meet you, Winnie.
蘇聯人說
You know, the Russians, they... they're saying
整個登月過程是我們在攝影棚裏拍的
that we shot the whole thing on a soundstage.
真不知道這種瘋狂的想法是從哪來的
I wonder where they got a crazy idea like that.
誰在乎他們怎麼想啊?
Who cares what they think?
就算沒人相信 真相依然是真相
Truth is still the truth even if nobody believes it.
就算所有人都信 謊言依然是謊言
Lie is still a lie even if everybody believes it.
你這次做得真完美
You know, you really nailed this.
連月塵都如此逼真
All the way down to the lunar dust.
可惜都是假的
Too bad it's all fake.
這是假的嗎?
Was that fake?
不是 感覺非常真實
No, that felt very real.
(政府財產 非請莫入)
十二 十一 十 九... 點火程序 五...
Twelve, eleven, ten, nine... Ignition sequence, five...